<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>security on KrakenD - Open source API Gateway</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/tags/security/</link><description>Recent content in security on KrakenD - Open source API Gateway</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.krakend.io/tags/security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>KrakenD Enterprise 2.2.1 (bugfixing) released</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-ee-2.2.1-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-ee-2.2.1-release-notes/</guid><description>The new KrakenD Enterprise version 2.2.1 is already available for install or upgrade. This patch version does not bring significant new functionality (except for AMQP) but includes a few fixes.
Summary of changes Enables backoff strategies for AMQP producers and consumers, and fixes OpenAPI generation issues.
AMQP consumers and producers offer now retries with several backoff strategies. Request modifier plugin loader is now hardened and is more strict to prevent human error.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD Enterprise 2.1.2 (security fix) released</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-ee-2.1.2-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-ee-2.1.2-release-notes/</guid><description>The new KrakenD Enterprise version 2.1.2 is already available for install or upgrade. This patch version does not bring significant new functionality but updates dependencies that have security vulnerabilities and adds a few fixes:
Summary of changes The patch v2.1.2 updates dependencies that have security vulnerabilities.
Add the content-type header when returning errors Upgrade from Go 1.19.3 to Go 1.19.5, which includes security fixes to the net/http, crypto/x509, and os packages, among others.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD 2.1.4 (security fix) released</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.1.4-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.1.4-release-notes/</guid><description>The new KrakenD version 2.1.4 is now available. This patch version does not bring significant new functionality but updates dependencies that have security vulnerabilities and adds a few fixes:
Summary of changes Corrects a bug when caching Gzipped content and adds the Content-Type header when returning errors.
Add the Content-Type header when returning errors Upgrade from Go 1.19.3 to Go 1.19.5, which includes security fixes to the net/http, crypto/x509, and os packages, among others.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD becomes a CNA (CVE Numbering Authority)</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-becomes-a-cna/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-becomes-a-cna/</guid><description>The Spanish National Cybersecurity Institute (INCIBE) announces today the addition of KrakenD as a CNA (CVE Numbering Authority). KrakenD assumes as its own, from this date, the best practices of this program.
KrakenD is now authorized by the CVE Program to assign CVE identifiers within its scope and its corresponding publication in the CNA section. Information technology and cybersecurity professionals use CVE Records to ensure they are discussing the same issue, and to coordinate their efforts to prioritize and address the vulnerabilities.</description></item><item><title>CVE-2022-1561: Crafted backend urls</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/cve-2022-1561-crafted-backend-urls/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/cve-2022-1561-crafted-backend-urls/</guid><description>&lt;p>There is a new vulnerability in the &lt;a href="https://luraproject.org/">Lura Project&lt;/a> software (which is the KrakenD&amp;rsquo;s engine). We have immediately corrected the problem in the subsequent release after its report. Please upgrade to the latest version.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>KrakenD unnaffected by Log4j</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/log4j-vulnerability/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/log4j-vulnerability/</guid><description>The year 2021 ended with terrible news for Java developers who saw how the Log4J vulnerabilities exposed their systems.
KrakenD is a Go application and not a Java application. Therefore, it is not affected by this vulnerability in any way. As a result, we didn&amp;rsquo;t want to add more noise to the chain of emails you could have probably received.
Nevertheless, during the past month, we had questions from customers who have Java systems behind KrakenD that could be vulnerable and other users that weren&amp;rsquo;t sure if KrakenD was impacted or not.</description></item></channel></rss>