<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Custom developer tools on KrakenD - Open source API Gateway</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/docs/developer/</link><description>Recent content in Custom developer tools on KrakenD - Open source API Gateway</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.krakend.io/docs/developer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>IDE integration</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/docs/developer/ide-integration/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/docs/developer/ide-integration/</guid><description>Automatic validation as you type, showing documentation while hovering an attribute, explanation of errors, and autocompletion of properties, are features that you get automatically while working with KrakenD.
For users of Visual Studio Code, Android Studio, JetBrains editors (PHPStorm, PyCharm, GoLand, WebStorm, IntelliJ IDEA&amp;hellip;), Eclipse, and other IDEs that have built-in json schema validation capabilities, there is nothing to install to have these features. Other editors can be used as well, but you will likely need to instal a JSON schema validator.</description></item><item><title>Automated integration tests</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/docs/developer/integration-tests/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/docs/developer/integration-tests/</guid><description>In addition to checking the syntax of your KrakenD configuration and make sure that the gateway can start, you can run integration tests to make sure that the gateway returns the expected content from the consumed backends. to make sure all endpoints are properly connected and that they reply with the expected content. To do that, you can use the library that KrakenD is relying on to run its integration tests, and complement the unit testing battery.</description></item><item><title>Hot reloading the configuration</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/docs/developer/hot-reload/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/docs/developer/hot-reload/</guid><description>When you want to restart KrakenD automatically after saving or changing files inside the configuration folder, the Docker image with the tag :watch can do this automatically for you.
It works whether you use flexible configuration or a single file (krakend.json or any other supported format).
The difference between the :watch image and :latest is that the KrakenD service wraps in a reflex watcher. When it detects that the configuration has changed, it restarts the service again, applying the changes.</description></item></channel></rss>