<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>DevOps on KrakenD - Open source API Gateway</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/categories/devops/</link><description>Recent content in DevOps on KrakenD - Open source API Gateway</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.krakend.io/categories/devops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Traffic mirroring: test your APIs automatically, without writing tests</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-shadow-testing/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-shadow-testing/</guid><description>Integration and load testing are in the list of best practices in our sector, but synthesizing good inputs for such tests and analyzing the results are usually two hard things to achieve. This post will show you how we suggest our customers set up a shadow testing system with minimal impact on the production environment and proper harness.
Quick overview As pointed out at https://cloud.google.com/architecture/application-deployment-and-testing-strategies
Testing new backend features by using the production load.</description></item><item><title>How we automated our RPM and DEB packaging with Docker</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/automating-linux-packaging/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2017 12:43:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/automating-linux-packaging/</guid><description>Everyone loves reaching the maximum number of available platforms for their software but this usually comes at a cost. In this article we will explain how we generated our packaging for Linux in an automated fashion, being faithful to our DevOps dogma.
Dockerize all the things! Our team uses both Ubuntu and MacOS X in desktop machines and KrakenD has been running and behaving in the same way in all the platforms because from day one we decided to run everything on Docker.</description></item></channel></rss>