<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Company Announcements on KrakenD - Open source API Gateway</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/categories/company-announcements/</link><description>Recent content in Company Announcements on KrakenD - Open source API Gateway</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.krakend.io/categories/company-announcements/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>KrakenD 2022 Recap: A Look Back at Our Major Milestones</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/2022-recap/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/2022-recap/</guid><description>We can&amp;rsquo;t believe it&amp;rsquo;s been six years since the first commit to KrakenD. It&amp;rsquo;s incredible how fast time passes when you have a purpose, and we&amp;rsquo;ve had a blast working on this project and seeing it grow. We are so grateful to everyone who has been with us on this journey.
At KrakenD, we are passionate about building an open-source API Gateway that pursues performance, scalability, and simplicity. This past year marked our first full year as an independent company.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD becomes a CNA (CVE Numbering Authority)</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-becomes-a-cna/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-becomes-a-cna/</guid><description>The Spanish National Cybersecurity Institute (INCIBE) announces today the addition of KrakenD as a CNA (CVE Numbering Authority). KrakenD assumes as its own, from this date, the best practices of this program.
KrakenD is now authorized by the CVE Program to assign CVE identifiers within its scope and its corresponding publication in the CNA section. Information technology and cybersecurity professionals use CVE Records to ensure they are discussing the same issue, and to coordinate their efforts to prioritize and address the vulnerabilities.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD partners with Child Rescue Coalition</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-child-rescue-coalition-partnership/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-child-rescue-coalition-partnership/</guid><description>Barcelona, September 19th 2022.- KrakenD announces today the partnership with Child Rescue Coalition. Child Rescue Coalition (CRC) is a nonprofit organization whose mission is to rescue children from sexual abuse by building technology for law enforcement to track, arrest and prosecute child predators. KrakenD has donated an unlimited commercial license (KrakenD Enterprise) to CRC to help them build and scale their APIs-oriented technological platform.
CRC has contributed to rescuing more than 3,200 children from sexual exploitation and abuse.</description></item><item><title>IBM proposes KrakenD to replace IBM Cloud API Gateway</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-alternative-ibm-api-cloud/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-alternative-ibm-api-cloud/</guid><description>The IBM Cloud API Gateway service provided traffic limiting, splitting, and authentication for Cloud Functions and Cloud Foundry users. Unfortunately, IBM&amp;rsquo;s API Gateway service was deprecated and shut down on August 31st, 2022. Existing endpoints will no longer route to their respective functions or apps.
A blog post by IBM Cloud published on June 8th provided some tips and recommendations for IBM Cloud API Gateway users. For those users who still require an API Gateway as part of their platform architecture, KrakenD has been suggested as an alternative.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD Now Available in the Azure Marketplace</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-partners-with-microsoft/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-partners-with-microsoft/</guid><description>BARCELONA, Spain — April 7, 2022
KrakenD today announced the availability of KrakenD API Gateway in the Microsoft Azure Marketplace, an online store providing applications and services for use on Microsoft Azure. KrakenD customers can now take advantage of the scalability, high availability, and security of Azure, with streamlined deployment and management.
The KrakenD API Gateway serves as a unified interface for managing incoming API requests and connecting to the correct destination, while supporting functionalities across security, authorization, traffic management, observability, and load balancing, among other services.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD unnaffected by Log4j</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/log4j-vulnerability/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/log4j-vulnerability/</guid><description>The year 2021 ended with terrible news for Java developers who saw how the Log4J vulnerabilities exposed their systems.
KrakenD is a Go application and not a Java application. Therefore, it is not affected by this vulnerability in any way. As a result, we didn&amp;rsquo;t want to add more noise to the chain of emails you could have probably received.
Nevertheless, during the past month, we had questions from customers who have Java systems behind KrakenD that could be vulnerable and other users that weren&amp;rsquo;t sure if KrakenD was impacted or not.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD Now Available on Auth0 Marketplace</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-auth0-announcement/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-auth0-announcement/</guid><description>Barcelona – 15th June 2020 – KrakenD today announced the availability of its API Gateway on Auth0 Marketplace, a catalog of trusted technology integrations to extend the functionality of Auth0’s identity management platform. KrakenD offers an ultra-performant API Gateway that allows companies to effortlessly adopt a microservices architecture through a powerful engine that can transform, aggregate, and remove data from their own or third-party services.
The KrakenD API Gateway serves as a unified interface for managing incoming API requests and connecting to the correct destination, while supporting functionalities across security, authorization, traffic management, observability, and load balancing, among others.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD framework becomes a Linux Foundation project</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-framework-joins-the-linux-foundation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-framework-joins-the-linux-foundation/</guid><description>Today, together with the Linux Foundation, we are announcing that the KrakenD framework, our core engine, has been donated to the Linux Foundation and is now the &amp;ldquo;Lura Project.&amp;rdquo;
The Lura Project&amp;rsquo;s mission is to offer an extendable, simple, and stateless high-performance API Gateway framework designed for cloud-native and on-prem setups. Rather than solving a specific use case, Lura provides a library of components, a framework for assembling them into custom API gateway systems like a Lego set.</description></item><item><title>Albert Garcia to expand KrakenD business.</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/albert-garcia-expand-krakend-business/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/albert-garcia-expand-krakend-business/</guid><description>Today, we are announcing that Albert Garcia recently joined KrakenD as Director of Business Development and member of the Board.
In his role, he will identify and develop new business opportunities to help expand even more the presence of KrakenD. Garcia will spearhead new markets and emerging trends, sales, and client relationship management, to name a few.
Having worked previously with him for more than 15 years, we know that Garcia is the right person at the right time for KrakenD.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD Usage Stats - March 2020</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/usage-stats-march-2020/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/usage-stats-march-2020/</guid><description>KrakenD servers with telemetry enabled help us to understand the usage of KrakenD in production. Last month we witnessed 356K running instances, and we wanted to share some data with you. 👇
From mid-March, we have seen an exciting increase in the number of KrakenD instances seen per day: x12! The trend is just beautiful, including the cumulative.
According to our internal definition, an instance is every time a KrakenD is started.</description></item><item><title>Open sourcing all 1st-year enterprise components</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/open-sourcing-enterprise-features/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2017 19:01:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/open-sourcing-enterprise-features/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been almost one year live, and what is known today as the KrakenD Enterprise components will be disclosed in the form of open-source repositories in the following weeks, and the action has already started, don&amp;rsquo;t miss it! In this post, we will explain the reasons behind this decision which might sound crazy from a business perspective in the first place. Why would anyone publish one year of paid software as free software?</description></item></channel></rss>