<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Company Announcements on KrakenD - Open source API Gateway</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/categories/company-announcements/</link><description>Recent content in Company Announcements on KrakenD - Open source API Gateway</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2025 08:12:51 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.krakend.io/categories/company-announcements/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>KrakenD joins Shop Circle to accelerate global expansion</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-joins-shopcircle/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2025 08:12:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-joins-shopcircle/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;KrakenD today announced it has joined Shop Circle, the global AI-driven software group that powers modern enterprises with mission-critical tools, in a strategic move that will accelerate KrakenD’s growth and global reach while preserving its vision, roadmap, and commitment to customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since its creation in 2016, KrakenD has been dedicated to building the fastest, most reliable, and developer-first API Gateway. Today it powers mission-critical infrastructures across government, finance, telecom, healthcare, and Fortune 500 companies, with deployments on millions of servers worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>KrakenD is Now SOC 2 Type II Certified: Our Commitment to Your Security, Officially Verified</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/soc2-certification-announcement/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 11:02:12 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/soc2-certification-announcement/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;If there is one thing we know about APIs, it’s that security is no joke, even if sometimes security jargon sounds like an acronym soup nobody wants for lunch. That is why today, we&amp;rsquo;re beyond pleased to share that &lt;strong&gt;KrakenD is now SOC 2 Type II certified&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After months of audits, sweat, and yes, the occasional “&lt;em&gt;Are we done yet?&lt;/em&gt;” moments from our team, we proudly hold this certification that shows we don’t just talk the security talk. We walk it, every day.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>New Look, Same Vision: KrakenD’s Website Redesign</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/new-look-same-vision/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 11:02:12 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/new-look-same-vision/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;At KrakenD, we’re excited to introduce our &lt;strong&gt;new website design&lt;/strong&gt;! While our logo and core branding remain consistent, the visual overhaul gives a fresh, modern look that better conveys what KrakenD is all about. We’ve focused on a style that highlights our core principles: &lt;strong&gt;simplicity, high performance, and efficiency&lt;/strong&gt;. The new design doesn’t just look better: it helps users quickly grasp KrakenD’s added value and how our solutions can simplify their API management.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>KrakenD Partners with Massil Technologies for India and Middle East</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-partners-with-massil-technologies/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 09:25:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-partners-with-massil-technologies/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;KrakenD is pleased to announce its exclusive partnership with &lt;strong&gt;Massil Technologies&lt;/strong&gt;, a leading IT services provider, as the official reseller and certified KrakenD integration partner in India and the Middle East. This strategic collaboration enhances KrakenD&amp;rsquo;s ability to provide localized API gateway solutions and support to customers across these regions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2016, &lt;strong&gt;Massil Technologies&lt;/strong&gt; is based in Hyderabad, India, and specializes in delivering rapid IT system integrations and cloud services. Their expertise spans multiple industries including BFSI, healthcare, logistics, and telecom. Known for their customer-centric approach, Massil has a reputation for driving digital transformation through API management, system integration, and advanced intelligent technologies.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>KrakenD 2023: Milestones and New Horizons</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/2023-recap/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/2023-recap/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;





&lt;img
 src="https://www.krakend.io/images/blog/company-announcements/2023-milestones.png"
 alt="2023 KrakenD Milestones"
 loading="lazy"
 width="1600"
 height="400"
 
 
 
/&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the year 2023 draws to a close, we at KrakenD are taking a moment to reflect on the incredible journey we&amp;rsquo;ve embarked upon together. It&amp;rsquo;s been a year marked by achievements, growth, and a relentless pursuit of excellence. We&amp;rsquo;re deeply grateful to our customers and the vibrant community that has supported us every step of the way. Your enthusiasm and trust have been the driving forces behind our success. As we look back at the milestones of 2023, we also extend our warmest wishes for a prosperous and positive 2024, hoping to continue this exciting adventure with all of you.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>KrakenD Training: The Definitive Certification Program for API Gateway Mastery</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-api-gateway-training-certification/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2023 13:25:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-api-gateway-training-certification/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;





&lt;img
 src="https://www.krakend.io/images/blog/company-announcements/krakend-training-header.png"
 alt="KrakenD Training"
 loading="lazy"
 width="1600"
 height="400"
 
 
 
/&gt;


We&amp;rsquo;re thrilled to unveil &lt;a href="https://training.krakend.io"&gt;KrakenD Training&lt;/a&gt;, a certification program that stands out in its depth and breadth. Crafted by the very engineers who developed KrakenD, this program is designed for tech professionals who are serious about mastering the full spectrum of features offered by KrakenD&amp;rsquo;s API Gateway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="why-choose-krakend-training"&gt;Why Choose KrakenD Training?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an industry where specialized knowledge is your strongest asset, KrakenD Training offers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technical Depth&lt;/strong&gt;: The course covers KrakenD&amp;rsquo;s extensive feature set, ensuring you become proficient in a wide range of use cases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Practical Application&lt;/strong&gt;: The curriculum is replete with real-world examples, making the acquired knowledge immediately applicable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Certification&lt;/strong&gt;: Earn an official KrakenD certification upon completion, a solid validation of your expertise in the field.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="a-closer-look-at-the-curriculum"&gt;A Closer Look at the Curriculum&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The course is meticulously segmented into specialized modules, each designed to offer a deep understanding of crucial aspects of KrakenD:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>KrakenD 2022 Recap: A Look Back at Our Major Milestones</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/2022-recap/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/2022-recap/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We can&amp;rsquo;t believe it&amp;rsquo;s been six years since &lt;a href="https://github.com/luraproject/lura/commit/1288ae34a481198a9bce2eb8e0aabace40bdb048"&gt;the first commit to KrakenD&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s incredible how fast time passes when you have a purpose, and we&amp;rsquo;ve had a blast working on this project and seeing it grow. We are so grateful to everyone who has been with us on this journey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At KrakenD, &lt;strong&gt;we are passionate about building an open-source API Gateway that pursues performance, scalability, and simplicity&lt;/strong&gt;. This past year marked our first full year as an independent company. It&amp;rsquo;s been a fantastic ride, and we can&amp;rsquo;t wait to see what the future holds for KrakenD.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>KrakenD becomes a CNA (CVE Numbering Authority)</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-becomes-a-cna/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-becomes-a-cna/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;









&lt;img
src="https://www.krakend.io/images/cve.svg"
alt="CVE"
loading="lazy"
width="320.65"
height="93.91"



/&gt;


The Spanish National Cybersecurity Institute (INCIBE) &lt;a href="https://www.incibe.es/incibe-cert/asignacion-publicacion-cve/cna-participantes/krakend"&gt;announces today&lt;/a&gt; the addition of KrakenD as a CNA (CVE Numbering Authority). KrakenD assumes as its own, from this date, the best practices of this program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KrakenD is now authorized by the CVE Program to assign CVE identifiers within its &lt;a href="https://www.cve.org/PartnerInformation/ListofPartners/partner/KrakenD"&gt;scope&lt;/a&gt; and its corresponding publication in the CNA &lt;a href="https://www.incibe.es/incibe-cert/asignacion-publicacion-cve"&gt;section&lt;/a&gt;. Information technology and cybersecurity professionals use CVE Records to ensure they are discussing the same issue, and to coordinate their efforts to prioritize and address the vulnerabilities.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>KrakenD partners with Child Rescue Coalition</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-child-rescue-coalition-partnership/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-child-rescue-coalition-partnership/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Barcelona, September 19th 2022&lt;/em&gt;.- KrakenD announces today the partnership with Child Rescue Coalition. Child Rescue Coalition (CRC) is a nonprofit organization whose mission is to rescue children from sexual abuse by building technology for law enforcement to track, arrest and prosecute child predators. &lt;strong&gt;KrakenD has donated an unlimited commercial license (KrakenD Enterprise) to CRC to help them build and scale their APIs-oriented technological platform&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CRC has contributed to rescuing more than 3,200 children from sexual exploitation and abuse. It has also arrested more than 14,000 dangerous predators, preventing the abuse of more than 700,000 children across the globe.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>IBM proposes KrakenD to replace IBM Cloud API Gateway</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-alternative-ibm-api-cloud/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-alternative-ibm-api-cloud/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The IBM Cloud API Gateway service provided traffic limiting, splitting, and authentication for Cloud Functions and Cloud Foundry users. Unfortunately, &lt;strong&gt;IBM&amp;rsquo;s API Gateway service was deprecated and shut down on August 31st, 2022&lt;/strong&gt;. Existing endpoints will no longer route to their respective functions or apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A blog post by IBM Cloud published on June 8th provided some &lt;a href="https://www.ibm.com/cloud/blog/announcements/api-gateway-migration-options-for-ibm-cloud-function-users"&gt;tips and recommendations for IBM Cloud API Gateway users&lt;/a&gt;. For those users who still require an API Gateway as part of their platform architecture, &lt;strong&gt;KrakenD has been suggested as an alternative&lt;/strong&gt;. We are glad to be included in the two alternatives proposed by IBM to their users, along with Kong.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>KrakenD Now Available in the Azure Marketplace</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-partners-with-microsoft/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-partners-with-microsoft/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;BARCELONA, Spain — April 7, 2022&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KrakenD today announced the &lt;strong&gt;availability of KrakenD API Gateway in the Microsoft Azure Marketplace&lt;/strong&gt;, an online store providing applications and services for use on Microsoft Azure. KrakenD customers can now take advantage of the scalability, high availability, and security of Azure, with streamlined deployment and management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The KrakenD API Gateway serves as a unified interface for managing incoming API requests and connecting to the correct destination, while supporting functionalities across security, authorization, traffic management, observability, and load balancing, among other services. With quick deployment from the Azure Marketplace, KrakenD helps developers to easily create modern, scalable, and performant APIs with a straightforward implementation.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>KrakenD unnaffected by Log4j</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/log4j-vulnerability/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/log4j-vulnerability/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The year 2021 ended with terrible news for Java developers who saw how the Log4J vulnerabilities exposed their systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;KrakenD is a Go application and not a Java application. Therefore, it is not affected by this vulnerability in any way&lt;/strong&gt;. As a result, we didn&amp;rsquo;t want to add more noise to the chain of emails you could have probably received.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, during the past month, we had questions from customers who have &lt;strong&gt;Java systems behind KrakenD&lt;/strong&gt; that could be vulnerable and other users that weren&amp;rsquo;t sure if KrakenD was impacted or not. So we want to explain in this email what can KrakenD do to help.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>KrakenD Now Available on Auth0 Marketplace</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-auth0-announcement/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-auth0-announcement/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Barcelona – 15th June 2020&lt;/strong&gt; – KrakenD today announced the availability of its API Gateway on &lt;a href="https://marketplace.auth0.com/"&gt;Auth0 Marketplace&lt;/a&gt;, a catalog of trusted technology integrations to extend the functionality of Auth0’s identity management platform. KrakenD offers an ultra-performant API Gateway that allows companies to effortlessly adopt a microservices architecture through a powerful engine that can transform, aggregate, and remove data from their own or third-party services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The KrakenD API Gateway serves as a unified interface for managing incoming API requests and connecting to the correct destination, while supporting functionalities across security, authorization, traffic management, observability, and load balancing, among others. When coupled with identity management, KrakenD helps developers create modern, scalable, and performant APIs with straightforward implementation. KrakenD controls user and machine access to a company’s business APIs, working in perfect symbiosis with Auth0 to do so securely.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>KrakenD framework becomes a Linux Foundation project</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-framework-joins-the-linux-foundation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-framework-joins-the-linux-foundation/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Today, &lt;a href="https://www.linuxfoundation.org/press/press-release/open-source-api-gateway-krakend-becomes-linux-foundation-project"&gt;together with the Linux Foundation&lt;/a&gt;, we are announcing that the KrakenD framework, our core engine, has been &lt;strong&gt;donated to the Linux Foundation and is now the &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="https://luraproject.org"&gt;Lura Project&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;





&lt;img
 src="https://www.krakend.io/images/blog/header-lura-linux-foundation.png"
 alt="KrakenD framework joins the Linux Foundation"
 loading="lazy"
 width="2400"
 height="1714"
 
 
 
/&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lura Project&amp;rsquo;s mission is to offer an extendable, simple, and stateless high-performance API Gateway framework designed for cloud-native and on-prem setups. Rather than solving a specific use case, Lura provides a library of components, a framework for assembling them into custom API gateway systems like a Lego set.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Albert Garcia to expand KrakenD business.</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/albert-garcia-expand-krakend-business/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/albert-garcia-expand-krakend-business/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Today, we are announcing that &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/obokaman/"&gt;Albert Garcia&lt;/a&gt; recently joined KrakenD as &lt;strong&gt;Director of Business Development&lt;/strong&gt; and member of the Board.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In his role, he will identify and develop new business opportunities to help expand even more the presence of KrakenD. Garcia will spearhead new markets and emerging trends, sales, and client relationship management, to name a few.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having worked previously with him for more than 15 years, we know that Garcia is the right person at the right time for KrakenD. His powerful entrepreneurial mindset, passion, and hunger for greatness will only make KrakenD grow stronger.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>KrakenD Usage Stats - March 2020</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/usage-stats-march-2020/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/usage-stats-march-2020/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;KrakenD servers with telemetry enabled help us to understand the usage of KrakenD in production. Last month we witnessed &lt;strong&gt;356K running instances&lt;/strong&gt;, and we wanted to share some data with you. 👇&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From mid-March, we have seen an exciting increase in the number of KrakenD instances seen per day: x12! The trend is just beautiful, including the cumulative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;





&lt;img
 src="https://www.krakend.io/images/blog/usage-march-2020/x12-instances.png"
 alt="Instances"
 loading="lazy"
 width="1073"
 height="249"
 
 
 
/&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to our internal definition, an instance is every time a KrakenD is started. And several instances of KrakenD sharing a common configuration form a &lt;strong&gt;cluster&lt;/strong&gt;. Last month we had 13.604 clusters.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Open sourcing all 1st-year enterprise components</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/open-sourcing-enterprise-features/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2017 19:01:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/open-sourcing-enterprise-features/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been almost one year live, and what is known today as the KrakenD Enterprise components will be disclosed in the form of open-source repositories in the following weeks, and the action has already started, don&amp;rsquo;t miss it! In this post, we will explain the reasons behind this decision which might sound crazy from a business perspective in the first place. Why would anyone publish one year of paid software as free software?&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>