<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>KrakenD API Gateway - Enterprise Edition Overview on KrakenD - Open source API Gateway</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/docs/enterprise/overview/</link><description>Recent content in KrakenD API Gateway - Enterprise Edition Overview on KrakenD - Open source API Gateway</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.krakend.io/docs/enterprise/overview/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Installing KrakenD Enterprise</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/docs/enterprise/overview/installing/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/docs/enterprise/overview/installing/</guid><description>KrakenD Enterprise is delivered in several formats, including Docker, Linux packages (deb, rpm) and generic installation options.
Find your KrakenD License email To download any Enterprise binaries, check your inbox and find our license activation email with the license details to use the Enterprise content. Don&amp;rsquo;t have one? Ask for a trial version.
Managing the License Ask for a trial Docker If you are already familiar with Docker, the easiest way to get started is by pulling our KrakenD image</description></item><item><title>Running KrakenD Enterprise: Available commands</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/docs/enterprise/overview/run/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/docs/enterprise/overview/run/</guid><description>After installing KrakenD Enterprise, you can start using it by typing krakend help:
The krakend command&amp;nbsp; $krakend ╓▄█ ▄▄▌ ╓██████▄µ ▐███ ▄███╨▐███▄██H╗██████▄ ║██▌ ,▄███╨ ▄██████▄ ▓██▌█████▄ ███▀╙╙▀▀███╕ ▐███▄███▀ ▐█████▀&amp;#34;╙▀▀&amp;#34;╙▀███ ║███▄███┘ ███▀&amp;#34;&amp;#34;▀███ ████▀╙▀███H ███ ╙███ ▐██████▌ ▐███⌐ ,▄████████M║██████▄ ║██████████M███▌ ███H ███ ,███ ▐███╨▀███µ ▐███ ███▌ ,███M║███╙▀███ ███▄```▄▄` ███▌ ███H ███,,,╓▄███▀ ▐███ ╙███▄▐███ ╙█████████M║██▌ ╙███▄`▀███████╨ ███▌ ███H █████████▀ `` `&amp;#39;` Version: 2.11.0-ee KrakenD is a high-performance API gateway that helps you publish, secure, control, and monitor your services Usage: krakend [command] Available Commands: audit Audits a KrakenD configuration.</description></item><item><title>Managing the LICENSE file</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/docs/enterprise/overview/license-file/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/docs/enterprise/overview/license-file/</guid><description>To run the Enterprise software, you must provide a valid license. The license file is included in an email with the download link. The file is named LICENSE by default (no extension), although you can change its location and name as long as you let KrakenD know.
When the license file is expired, incorrect, or missing, KrakenD won&amp;rsquo;t start. If KrakenD is running and the license expires, the service shuts down.</description></item><item><title>Enterprise plugins</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/docs/enterprise/overview/plugins/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/docs/enterprise/overview/plugins/</guid><description>Some of the functionality offered by KrakenD Enterprise is presented as plugins, and other as components. Although functionality offered as plugins is decreasing, it&amp;rsquo;s important to understand a few concepts and particularities of plugins before you start using them. For each functionality of Enterprise offered as a plugin, you will see in its documentation how to use it.
What is a plugin? A plugin is a soft-linked library; thus, a separated binary file (.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD API Gateway Enterprise Playground</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/docs/enterprise/overview/playground/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/docs/enterprise/overview/playground/</guid><description>The KrakenD Enterprise Playground is a Docker Compose demonstration environment that puts together the necessary pieces to get you started with our API Gateway, using example use-cases.
As KrakenD is an API gateway, we have added surrounding services:
Internal and third-party services that feed the gateway Authentication/authorization examples, including JWT token-based authentication with Auth0 integration, a JWT token revoker, API-Key-based authentication, and basic authentication. Static assets to test the by KrakenD Static Server based on disk content Integrations with Grafana+Influx (metrics), ELK (log storing and visualization), and Jaeger (tracing).</description></item><item><title>Lura vs. KrakenD</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/docs/enterprise/overview/lura-vs-krakend/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/docs/enterprise/overview/lura-vs-krakend/</guid><description>If you had a quick look at our git repositories or the documentation, you might be confused at first, as there is something called the Lura Project and also KrakenD.
TL;DR; Difference between Lura, KrakenD, and Enterprise Lura is the KrakenD&amp;rsquo;s engine. Formerly known as &amp;ldquo;KrakenD framework&amp;rdquo; until we donated it to The Linux Foundation on 2021. It is not a product itself but a toolkit/set of libraries to build API gateways.</description></item><item><title>Comprehensive Guides for KrakenD API Gateway</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/docs/enterprise/overview/guides/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/docs/enterprise/overview/guides/</guid><description>The documentation in this site covers all the functionality of KrakenD API Gateway, but over time we have received from KrakenD users all kinds of tutorials, guides and other resources that illustrate how to do a specific thing. We have included below a few links, but you can share yours.
Add a link User-contributed resources Getting started with KrakenD on Kubernetes / AKS by Christian Dennig (Cloud Solution Architect @ Microsoft) Build and Deploy with Kubernetes, Helm, and Skaffold by Fabijan Bajo (Technical Lead, DevOps / Cloud Infrastructure @ IBM) Microservices with Micronaut, KrakenD and Consul by Piotr Minkowski (Solution Architect @ Red Hat) How to Successfully Set Up KrakenD on GKE: A Step by Step Guide by Vijay Savanth on Hackernoon Writing Plugins using Golang by Ilya Nemtsev on Eventslooped Building Micro Services with .</description></item><item><title>Verifying packages (PGP and SHA256)</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/docs/enterprise/overview/verifying-packages/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/docs/enterprise/overview/verifying-packages/</guid><description>How to make sure what you are downloading is legit.
PGP We will check the detached signature PGP against our package KrakenD.
Term&amp;nbsp; $gpg --verify krakend_2.11.0_amd64_generic-linux.tar.gz.asc krakend_2.11.0_amd64_generic-linux.tar.gz gpg: Signature made Sun Mar 10 18:17:18 2019 UTC using RSA key ID 5DE6FD698AD6FDD2 gpg: Can&amp;#39;t check signature: public key not found We don&amp;rsquo;t have the packager public key (AB39BEA1) in our system. You need to retrieve the public key from a key server.</description></item></channel></rss>