<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Introduction to KrakenD Enterprise on KrakenD - Open source API Gateway</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/docs/enterprise/overview/</link><description>Recent content in Introduction to KrakenD Enterprise on KrakenD - Open source API Gateway</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.krakend.io/docs/enterprise/overview/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Installing KrakenD Enterprise</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/docs/enterprise/overview/installing/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/docs/enterprise/overview/installing/</guid><description>KrakenD Enterprise is delivered in several formats, including Docker, Linux packages (deb, rpm) and generic installation options.
Find your KrakenD License email To download any Enterprise binaries, check your inbox and find our license activation email with the license details to use the Enterprise content. Don&amp;rsquo;t have one? Ask for a trial version Docker If you are already familiar with Docker, the easiest way to get started is by pulling our KrakenD image</description></item><item><title>Running KrakenD</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/docs/enterprise/overview/run/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/docs/enterprise/overview/run/</guid><description>After installing KrakenD, you can start using it by typing krakend help:
The krakend command&amp;nbsp; $krakend ╓▄█ ▄▄▌ ╓██████▄µ ▐███ ▄███╨▐███▄██H╗██████▄ ║██▌ ,▄███╨ ▄██████▄ ▓██▌█████▄ ███▀╙╙▀▀███╕ ▐███▄███▀ ▐█████▀&amp;#34;╙▀▀&amp;#34;╙▀███ ║███▄███┘ ███▀&amp;#34;&amp;#34;▀███ ████▀╙▀███H ███ ╙███ ▐██████▌ ▐███⌐ ,▄████████M║██████▄ ║██████████M███▌ ███H ███ ,███ ▐███╨▀███µ ▐███ ███▌ ,███M║███╙▀███ ███▄```▄▄` ███▌ ███H ███,,,╓▄███▀ ▐███ ╙███▄▐███ ╙█████████M║██▌ ╙███▄`▀███████╨ ███▌ ███H █████████▀ `` `&amp;#39;` Version: 2.1.1 KrakenD is a declarative high-performance API gateway that helps you effortlessly adopt microservices Usage: krakend [command] Available Commands: check Validates that the configuration file is valid.</description></item><item><title>Managing the LICENSE file</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/docs/enterprise/overview/license-file/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/docs/enterprise/overview/license-file/</guid><description>To run the Enterprise software with all its capabilities you must provide a valid license. When you get a license from sales, its placement and format must comply with what the binary expects.
When the license file is incorrect, KrakenD warns you about it but the server will start anyway.
The message you will see when the server starts with an invalid or missing license file is:
Term&amp;nbsp; $krakend run -dec krakend.</description></item><item><title>Enterprise plugins</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/docs/enterprise/overview/plugins/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/docs/enterprise/overview/plugins/</guid><description>A great deal of the functionality offered by KrakenD Enterprise is presented as plugins, and other as components. It&amp;rsquo;s important to understand a few concepts and particularities of plugins before you start using them.
What is a plugin? A plugin is a soft-linked library; thus, a separated binary file (.so), that when running in conjunction with KrakenD, can participate in the processing. Plugins and middlewares are close concepts, but while middlewares are part of the KrakenD binary, plugins are not.</description></item><item><title>Lura vs. KrakenD</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/docs/enterprise/overview/lura-vs-krakend/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/docs/enterprise/overview/lura-vs-krakend/</guid><description>If you had a quick look at our git repositories or the documentation, you might be confused at first, as there is something called the Lura Project and also KrakenD.
TL;DR; Difference between Lura, KrakenD, and Enterprise Lura is the KrakenD&amp;rsquo;s engine. Formerly known as &amp;ldquo;KrakenD framework&amp;rdquo; until we donated it to The Linux Foundation on 2021. It is not a product itself but a toolkit/set of libraries to build API gateways.</description></item><item><title>The KrakenD Enterprise Playground</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/docs/enterprise/overview/playground/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/docs/enterprise/overview/playground/</guid><description>The KrakenD Enterprise Playground is a Docker Compose demonstration environment that puts together the necessary pieces to get you started with our API Gateway, using example use-cases.
As KrakenD is an API gateway, we have added surrounding services:
Internal and third-party services that feed the gateway Authentication/authorization examples, including JWT token-based authentication with Auth0 integration, a JWT token revoker, API-Key-based authentication, and basic authentication. Static assets to test the by KrakenD Static Server based on disk content Integrations with Grafana+Influx (metrics), ELK (log storing and visualization), and Jaeger (tracing).</description></item><item><title>Tutorials and Guides</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/docs/enterprise/overview/guides/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/docs/enterprise/overview/guides/</guid><description>The documentation in this site covers all the functionality of KrakenD API Gateway, but over time we have received from KrakenD users all kinds of tutorials, guides and other resources that illustrate how to do a specific thing. We have included below a few links, but you can share yours.
User-contributed resources Getting started with KrakenD on Kubernetes / AKS by Christian Dennig (Cloud Solution Architect @ Microsoft) Build and Deploy with Kubernetes, Helm, and Skaffold by Fabijan Bajo (Technical Lead, DevOps / Cloud Infrastructure @ IBM) Microservices with Micronaut, KrakenD and Consul by Piotr Minkowski (Solution Architect @ Red Hat) How to Successfully Set Up KrakenD on GKE: A Step by Step Guide by Vijay Savanth on Hackernoon Writing Plugins using Golang by Ilya Nemtsev on Eventslooped Building Micro Services with .</description></item><item><title>Verifying packages (PGP and SHA256)</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/docs/enterprise/overview/verifying-packages/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/docs/enterprise/overview/verifying-packages/</guid><description>How to make sure what you are downloading is legit.
PGP We will check the detached signature PGP against our package KrakenD.
Term&amp;nbsp; $gpg --verify krakend_2.1.1_amd64_generic-linux.tar.gz.asc krakend_2.1.1_amd64_generic-linux.tar.gz gpg: Signature made Sun Mar 10 18:17:18 2019 UTC using RSA key ID 5DE6FD698AD6FDD2 gpg: Can&amp;#39;t check signature: public key not found We don&amp;rsquo;t have the packager public key (AB39BEA1) in our system. You need to retrieve the public key from a key server.</description></item></channel></rss>