<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Security on KrakenD - Open source API Gateway</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/categories/security/</link><description>Recent content in Security on KrakenD - Open source API Gateway</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.krakend.io/categories/security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Upgrade to mitigate the Rapid Reset Attack vulnerability</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.4.6-ce-2.4.2-ee-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.4.6-ce-2.4.2-ee-release-notes/</guid><description>A new patch version KrakenD Enterprise 2.4.2, and another for KrakenD Community 2.4.6 is available on the download page and the Docker registry, addressing a critical security issue related to Distributed Denial of Service (DDoS) vulnerabilities in HTTP/2 server implementations
More specifically this upgrade addresses CVE-2023-44487 and CVE-2023-39325&amp;quot;, known as the &amp;ldquo;Rapid Reset Attack.&amp;rdquo;
These vulnerabilities have been rated with a CVSSv3 Score of 7.5 and are classified as having an important security impact.</description></item><item><title>Securing Your Microservices and APIs: The KrakenD Way</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/securing-your-microservices/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 13:25:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/securing-your-microservices/</guid><description>In today&amp;rsquo;s world, where everything is going digital, we can&amp;rsquo;t overemphasize the importance of keeping your APIs and microservices safe. Cyber threats are an everyday reality, and they don&amp;rsquo;t care how big or complex your infrastructure is. They just want a way in. This is where KrakenD, a leading API gateway company, steps in. We&amp;rsquo;ve got your back with our robust solution, built around a zero-trust policy, OWASP guidelines, and a bunch of other cool stuff to bolster your API security.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD CE 2.4.2 and EE 2.3.3 security fixes</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.4.2-ce-2.3.3-ee-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.4.2-ce-2.3.3-ee-release-notes/</guid><description>A new patch version KrakenD Enterprise 2.3.3, and another for KrakenD Community 2.4.2 is available on the download page and the Docker registry. Upgrading from any 2.x is backward compatible.
The following security fixes do not seem to have any impact on KrakenD after all the tests performed, but a patch is offered as a cautionary measure.
🚀 Summary of changes for CEv2.4 We have updated our internal libraries to rectify security issues identified in scans.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD 2.3.3 (patch version) released</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.3.3-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.3.3-release-notes/</guid><description>A new patch version KrakenD 2.3.3 is available on the download page and the Docker registry. Upgrading from any 2.x is backward compatible.
This release includes a security fix to mitigate SSL3 CVE-2023-1255 (Base Score: 5.9 MEDIUM) and new Lua helpers fo facilitate developments of custom business logic. The new Lua helpers are:
luaTable.new(), which returns a new table. t:keys(), which returns the sorted key names of a table t. luaList.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD becomes a CNA (CVE Numbering Authority)</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-becomes-a-cna/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-becomes-a-cna/</guid><description>The Spanish National Cybersecurity Institute (INCIBE) announces today the addition of KrakenD as a CNA (CVE Numbering Authority). KrakenD assumes as its own, from this date, the best practices of this program.
KrakenD is now authorized by the CVE Program to assign CVE identifiers within its scope and its corresponding publication in the CNA section. Information technology and cybersecurity professionals use CVE Records to ensure they are discussing the same issue, and to coordinate their efforts to prioritize and address the vulnerabilities.</description></item><item><title>Adressing CVE-2022-1561: Crafted backend urls</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/cve-2022-1561-crafted-backend-urls/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/cve-2022-1561-crafted-backend-urls/</guid><description>&lt;p>There is a new vulnerability in the &lt;a href="https://luraproject.org/">Lura Project&lt;/a> software (which is the KrakenD&amp;rsquo;s engine). We have immediately corrected the problem in the subsequent release after its report. Please upgrade to the latest version.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>KrakenD unnaffected by Log4j</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/log4j-vulnerability/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/log4j-vulnerability/</guid><description>The year 2021 ended with terrible news for Java developers who saw how the Log4J vulnerabilities exposed their systems.
KrakenD is a Go application and not a Java application. Therefore, it is not affected by this vulnerability in any way. As a result, we didn&amp;rsquo;t want to add more noise to the chain of emails you could have probably received.
Nevertheless, during the past month, we had questions from customers who have Java systems behind KrakenD that could be vulnerable and other users that weren&amp;rsquo;t sure if KrakenD was impacted or not.</description></item></channel></rss>