<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>enterprise on KrakenD - Open source API Gateway</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/tags/enterprise/</link><description>Recent content in enterprise on KrakenD - Open source API Gateway</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.krakend.io/tags/enterprise/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>KrakenD Enterprise 2.1 released</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-ee-2.1-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-ee-2.1-release-notes/</guid><description>The KrakenD team is pleased to announce the release of KrakenD Enterprise 2.1, already available for install or upgrade.
KrakenD EE 2.1 brings a lot of new functionality, including advanced manipulation with a JSON Query language, a Revoke Server to manage tokens in clusters, new Kibana and Grafana dashboards, faster encoding, a rewritten and richer NewRelic exporter, Websockets balancing, and much more. Apologies because we have added so much that the summary is not going to be short this time :)</description></item><item><title>KrakenD Enterprise 2.0 released!</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-ee-2.0-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-ee-2.0-release-notes/</guid><description>The KrakenD team is pleased to announce KrakenD Enterprise 2.0, already available for install or upgrade today.
KrakenD 2.0 is the awaited new major version of KrakenD bringing a lot of improvements to the API Gateway, including all the features and improvements of open source releases between v1.4 and v2.0.4.
KrakenD Enterprise adds API Analytics, IP Filtering, GraphQL, OpenAPI importers and exporters, integration tests, specific request/modifier plugins, Async Agents, backend response logging (dumper) and improves the existing WebSockets, API Keys, configuration syntax, New Relic reporting, logging, and router to put a few examples.</description></item></channel></rss>