<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Enterprise on KrakenD - Open source API Gateway</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/categories/enterprise/</link><description>Recent content in Enterprise on KrakenD - Open source API Gateway</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.krakend.io/categories/enterprise/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>KrakenD Usage Stats - March 2020</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/usage-stats-march-2020/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/usage-stats-march-2020/</guid><description>KrakenD servers with telemetry enabled help us to understand the usage of KrakenD in production. Last month we witnessed 356K running instances, and we wanted to share some data with you. 👇
From mid-March, we have seen an exciting increase in the number of KrakenD instances seen per day: x12! The trend is just beautiful, including the cumulative.
According to our internal definition, an instance is every time a KrakenD is started.</description></item><item><title>Open sourcing all enterprise components</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/open-sourcing-enterprise-features/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2017 19:01:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/open-sourcing-enterprise-features/</guid><description>What are known today as the KrakenD Enterprise components will be disclosed in the form of open source repositories in the following weeks, and the action has already started, don&amp;rsquo;t miss it! In this post we will explain the reasons behind this decision that might sound crazy from a business perspective in the first place. Why anyone would publish the paid software increment bits of an existing free software?
A look back&amp;hellip; If you are reading this post chances are that you know this already, in short KrakenD is the fastest API Gateway in the market.</description></item></channel></rss>