<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Enterprise on KrakenD - Open source API Gateway</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/categories/enterprise/</link><description>Recent content in Enterprise on KrakenD - Open source API Gateway</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.krakend.io/categories/enterprise/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>KrakenD Enterprise 1.3.0 released</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-ee-1.3-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-ee-1.3-release-notes/</guid><description>We are glad to announce that KrakenD Enterprise 1.3.0 is out. The new release comes with the following new features.
Summary of changes KrakenD Enterprise 1.3 includes everything in the Community v1.3 and adds generator commands for OpenAPI, Postman, and rendering PNG files with the configuration. It also adds support for wildcard routes.
New generate postman command New generate openapi command New generate config2dot command Support for wildcard routes Multiple identity providers Integration of secret providers Upgrading to the latest version is always advised.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD Usage Stats - March 2020</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/usage-stats-march-2020/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/usage-stats-march-2020/</guid><description>KrakenD servers with telemetry enabled help us to understand the usage of KrakenD in production. Last month we witnessed 356K running instances, and we wanted to share some data with you. 👇
From mid-March, we have seen an exciting increase in the number of KrakenD instances seen per day: x12! The trend is just beautiful, including the cumulative.
According to our internal definition, an instance is every time a KrakenD is started.</description></item><item><title>Open sourcing all 1st-year enterprise components</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/open-sourcing-enterprise-features/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2017 19:01:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/open-sourcing-enterprise-features/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been almost one year live, and what is known today as the KrakenD Enterprise components will be disclosed in the form of open-source repositories in the following weeks, and the action has already started, don&amp;rsquo;t miss it! In this post, we will explain the reasons behind this decision which might sound crazy from a business perspective in the first place. Why would anyone publish one year of paid software as free software?</description></item></channel></rss>