<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>docker on KrakenD - Open source API Gateway</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/tags/docker/</link><description>Recent content in docker on KrakenD - Open source API Gateway</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.krakend.io/tags/docker/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>KrakenD Now Available in the Azure Marketplace</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-partners-with-microsoft/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-partners-with-microsoft/</guid><description>BARCELONA, Spain — April 7, 2022
KrakenD today announced the availability of KrakenD API Gateway in the Microsoft Azure Marketplace, an online store providing applications and services for use on Microsoft Azure. KrakenD customers can now take advantage of the scalability, high availability, and security of Azure, with streamlined deployment and management.
The KrakenD API Gateway serves as a unified interface for managing incoming API requests and connecting to the correct destination, while supporting functionalities across security, authorization, traffic management, observability, and load balancing, among other services.</description></item><item><title>Reloading the config with Reflex and Docker</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/reloading-the-krakend-configuration/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 11:06:53 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/reloading-the-krakend-configuration/</guid><description>Read the new documentation This is an article from 2018. You might want to see the Hot reload documentation. A recurrent question when we go around is if KrakenD configuration can be hot-reloaded, this is changing endpoints, backends, or any other configuration of the gateway while it&amp;rsquo;s running. The short answer is: No, you can&amp;rsquo;t. You must restart the server. And although we might have something to alleviate this, let us explain first why we don&amp;rsquo;t support such a feature:</description></item><item><title>Running the KrakenD API Gateway on Kubernetes</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-on-kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2018 18:47:03 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-on-kubernetes/</guid><description>In this article we are going to show how to configure and deploy the KrakenD API Gateway in a kubernetes environment.
We will use for the demonstration Minikube so you cant test it in your own local machine.
Let&amp;rsquo;s get started!
Setting up a local Kubernetes We will run Kubernetes locally thanks to Minikube. Just follow the README in the project for the installation and the Quickstart section. Installing minikube it&amp;rsquo;s quick and easy.</description></item><item><title>Automating our RPM/DEB packaging with Docker</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/automating-linux-packaging/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2017 12:43:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/automating-linux-packaging/</guid><description>Everyone loves reaching the maximum number of available platforms for their software but this usually comes at a cost. In this article we will explain how we generated our packaging for Linux in an automated fashion, being faithful to our DevOps dogma.
Dockerize all the things! Our dev team uses both Linux and MacOS X in desktop machines and KrakenD has been running and behaving in the same way in all the platforms because from day one we decided to run everything on Docker.</description></item></channel></rss>