<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>release notes on KrakenD - Open source API Gateway</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/tags/release-notes/</link><description>Recent content in release notes on KrakenD - Open source API Gateway</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.krakend.io/tags/release-notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>KrakenD 2.3.2 (patch version) released</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.3.2-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.3.2-release-notes/</guid><description>A new patch version KrakenD 2.3.2 is available on the download page and the Docker registry. Upgrading from any 2.x is backward compatible.
Summary of changes Fixed plugin builder and corrected edge cases in JWT validation.
Custom plugins: Alpine image builder fixed for ARM64 JWT: Panic when receiving an invalid number of claims JWT: Remove misleading error log when no global cache is defined JWT: index out of range Upgrade to Go version 1.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD 2.3.1 (patch version) released</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.3.1-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.3.1-release-notes/</guid><description>A new patch version KrakenD 2.3.1 is available to download page. Upgrading from any 2.x is backwards compatible.
Summary of changes The new TLS Client functionality was not included in the release.
The deny attribute did not work on the third nesting level and above. The new tls_client attribute was not yet included Upgrading to the latest version is always advised. Compare versions</description></item><item><title>KrakenD CE v2.3 released!</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.3-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.3-release-notes/</guid><description>The KrakenD team is pleased to announce the release of KrakenD Community Edition v2.3, which improves connectivity with backends, caching, and adds the possibility to play with KrakenD using the web Designer directly.
You can get v2.3 packaged for several options from the download page.
Summary of changes The v2.3 adds more connectivity options with backends, caching, and adds the possibility to load changes into a local KrakenD using the Designer (UI) directly.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD Enterprise 2.2.1 (bugfixing) released</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-ee-2.2.1-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-ee-2.2.1-release-notes/</guid><description>The new KrakenD Enterprise version 2.2.1 is already available for install or upgrade. This patch version does not bring significant new functionality (except for AMQP) but includes a few fixes.
Summary of changes Enables backoff strategies for AMQP producers and consumers, and fixes OpenAPI generation issues.
AMQP consumers and producers offer now retries with several backoff strategies. Request modifier plugin loader is now hardened and is more strict to prevent human error.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD Enterprise 2.2 released</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-ee-2.2-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-ee-2.2-release-notes/</guid><description>The new KrakenD Enterprise version 2.2 is now available, and it&amp;rsquo;s supercharged: Introduces dynamic routing based on headers and query strings, adds a security policies engine, upgrades to OpenAPI 3, improves SOAP integration, default gzip compression and a lot more&amp;hellip;
Below there is a summary of changes and an introduction to some of these new features.
Summary of changes The v2.2. introduces a new security policies engine, routing based on headers, OpenAPI 3, SOAP integration with custom body generation, everything on Community 2.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD 2.2.1 (patch version) released</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.2.1-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.2.1-release-notes/</guid><description>A new patch version KrakenD 2.2.1 is available to download page. Upgrading from any 2.x does not require changes in the configuration.
Summary of changes Fixes a memory leak on Shadow Proxies.
Fixed memory leak on Shadow Proxies when the response wasn&amp;rsquo;t a 200 Fixed audit command that would still warn on some fixed issues Upgraded Go to version 1.20.1 Upgrading to the latest version is always advised.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD CE v2.2 released!</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.2-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.2-release-notes/</guid><description>The KrakenD team is pleased to announce the release of KrakenD Community Edition v2.2. It introduces a new security audit command (krakend audit) that parses and analyzes your configurations and outputs security recommendations. We have designed it to run as a standalone command or integrated it into your existing CI/CD pipeline to avoid dangerous configurations, such as unwillingly disabling the TLS, setting excessive timeouts, unprotected endpoints, or similar scenarios.
You can get v2.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD Enterprise 2.1.2 (security fix) released</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-ee-2.1.2-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-ee-2.1.2-release-notes/</guid><description>The new KrakenD Enterprise version 2.1.2 is already available for install or upgrade. This patch version does not bring significant new functionality but updates dependencies that have security vulnerabilities and adds a few fixes:
Summary of changes The patch v2.1.2 updates dependencies that have security vulnerabilities.
Add the content-type header when returning errors Upgrade from Go 1.19.3 to Go 1.19.5, which includes security fixes to the net/http, crypto/x509, and os packages amongst others.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD 2.1.4 (security fix) released</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.1.4-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.1.4-release-notes/</guid><description>The new KrakenD version 2.1.4 is now available. This patch version does not bring significant new functionality but updates dependencies that have security vulnerabilities and adds a few fixes:
Summary of changes Corrects a bug when caching Gzipped content and adds the Content-Type header when returning errors.
Add the Content-Type header when returning errors Upgrade from Go 1.19.3 to Go 1.19.5, which includes security fixes to the net/http, crypto/x509, and os packages amongst others.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD 2.1.1 EE (patch version) released</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-ee-2.1.1-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-ee-2.1.1-release-notes/</guid><description>The new KrakenD Enterprise version 2.1.1 is already available for install or upgrade. This patch version does not bring new API Gateway functionality but adds support for ARM64 and other improvements.
Summary of changes The patch v2.1.1 fixes logging on the wildcard and a race condition on OpenAPI generation.
Fix OpenAPI race condition Fix wildcard plugin logger messages Upgrading to the latest version is always advised.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD 2.1.3 (patch version) released</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.1.3-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.1.3-release-notes/</guid><description>The new KrakenD version 2.1.3 is now available. This patch version does not bring new API Gateway functionality but adds support for ARM64 and other improvements.
Summary of changes ARM64 support, and obfuscate the KrakenD version header.
Now officially supporting ARM64 architectures, releasing new Docker containers and packages. Performance improvement on Lambda usage A new flag, hide_version_header, placed in the router settings, allows obfuscating the X-Krakend-Version header.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD Enterprise 2.1 released</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-ee-2.1-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-ee-2.1-release-notes/</guid><description>The KrakenD team is pleased to announce the release of KrakenD Enterprise 2.1, already available for install or upgrade.
Apologies because we have added so much that the summary is not going to be short this time :)
Summary of changes KrakenD Enterprise v2.1 brings a lot of new functionality, including advanced manipulation with a JSON Query language, a Revoke Server to manage tokens in clusters, new Kibana and Grafana dashboards, faster encoding, a rewritten and richer NewRelic exporter, Websockets balancing, and much more.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD 2.1.2 (patch version) released</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.1.2-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.1.2-release-notes/</guid><description>A new patch version KrakenD 2.1.2 is available to download page. This release fixes a bug while parsing placeholders in endpoint.
Summary of changes Corrects a bug with paramaters sent to the backend
Some requests sent to backend didn&amp;rsquo;t have the parameters replaced from the client URL Upgrading to the latest version is always advised. Compare versions</description></item><item><title>KrakenD 2.1.1 (patch version) released</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.1.1-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.1.1-release-notes/</guid><description>A new patch version KrakenD 2.1.1 is available to download page. In addition to the patch, we have created a new plugin-builder Docker image for those who compile custom plugins.
Summary of changes Adds a Docker image to build plugins and fixes issues with the JOSE and Lua packages.
Bot Detector: Avoid aborting with an error Influx: Logs normalized for better consistency JOSE: Use a sempahore to orchestrate the concurrent warm up of the JWK caches Lambda: Upgrade the AWS SDK version used (by @boris154) The krakend check command did not accept configurations with zero number of endpoints.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD 2.1 released!</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.1-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.1-release-notes/</guid><description>The KrakenD team is pleased to announce the release of KrakenD 2.1. You can get it packaged from the download page.
KrakenD 2.1 brings a new ready-to-use Kibana dashboard, an updated Grafana Dashboard for InfluxDB v2 and more features and bugfixes described below:
Summary of changes KrakenD 2.1 brings a new ready-to-use Kibana dashboard, an updated Grafana Dashboard for InfluxDB v2 and more features and bugfixes
New repository Telemetry Dashboards, including Kibana, Grafana, Logstash, and Influx v2 Added a krakend version command that outputs the KrakenD, Go, and Glibc versions.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD Enterprise 2.0 released!</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-ee-2.0-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-ee-2.0-release-notes/</guid><description>The KrakenD team is pleased to announce KrakenD Enterprise 2.0, already available for install or upgrade today.
KrakenD 2.0 is the awaited new major version of KrakenD bringing a lot of improvements to the API Gateway, including all the features and improvements of open source releases between v1.4 and v2.0.4.
Summary of changes KrakenD Enterprise 2.0 is a major rework and needs migration. API Analytics, IP Filtering, GraphQL, OpenAPI importers and exporters, integration tests, specific request/modifier plugins, Async Agents, backend response logging (dumper) and improves the existing WebSockets, API Keys, configuration syntax, New Relic reporting, logging, and router to put a few examples.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD 2.0 released!</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.0-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.0-release-notes/</guid><description>The KrakenD team is pleased to announce the major release KrakenD 2.0. You can get it packaged from the download page.
Summary of changes KrakenD 2.0 is the new major version of KrakenD bringing a lot of improvements to the API Gateway. GraphQL, specific request/modifier plugins, async agents, easier configuration, better logging, and a more flexible router to put a few examples.
REST to GraphQL conversion, or direct consumption of GraphQL through the gateway Backend response logging New plugin types (request/response) Plenty of new configurable router flags The krakend check adds verbosity level A new command krakend check-plugin for quicker development of custom plugins Shortened configuration namespaces.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD 1.4.0 released</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-1.4-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-1.4-release-notes/</guid><description>The KrakenD team is pleased to announce the release of KrakenD 1.4.0. You can get it packaged from the download page.
Summary of changes KrakenD 1.4 is the last version of the 1.x family and primarily replaces the KrakenD Framework with the Lura Project and includes minor bug fixing and an extended flexible configuration. The next release with the new functionality will be 2.0.
All dependencies for the framework moved to Lura The json-collection output encoding allows returning collections directly Added Sprig functions to Flexible Configuration Allow the propagation of nested claims using dot notation (JWT) Add the del method to Lua Upgrading to the latest version is always advised.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD Enterprise 1.3.0 released</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-ee-1.3-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-ee-1.3-release-notes/</guid><description>We are glad to announce that KrakenD Enterprise 1.3.0 is out. The new release comes with the following new features.
Summary of changes KrakenD Enterprise 1.3 includes everything in the community edition and adds generator commands for OpenAPI, Postman, and rendering PNG files with the configuration. It also adds support for wildcard routes.
New generate postman command New generate openapi command New generate config2dot command Support for wildcard routes Multiple identity providers Integration of secret providers Upgrading to the latest version is always advised.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD 1.3.0 released</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-1.3-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-1.3-release-notes/</guid><description>The KrakenD team is pleased to announce the release of KrakenD 1.3.0. You can get it packaged from the download page.
Summary of changes KrakenD 1.3.0 makes focus on completing the RBAC system regarding JWT.
Scopes validation (thanks to @chrisdennig) Extract and forward claims as headers (thanks to @chrisdennig) Support for Oracle Identity Cloud Service by allowing key identifers other than kid such as x5t or kid_x5t (contribution from Oracle) Allow loading of local JWK files Integration with secret providers such as, Amazon KMS, Azure&amp;rsquo;s Key Vault, Google Cloud KMS, Hashicorp&amp;rsquo;s Vault, Encrypted or plain base64 file Expose router request host to Lua virtual machine (thanks to Marc Ruiz from Stayforlong) Add X-Forwarded-Host header (thanks to Marc Ruiz from Stayforlong) Allow the extraction of client IP from custom headers Add debugging information to CORS component The Etcd component is no longer loaded in KrakenD-CE (but the repository is available for custom integrations) The WASM-based emulator in KrakenDesigner has been removed.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD 1.2.0 released</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-1.2-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-1.2-release-notes/</guid><description>The KrakenD team is pleased to announce the release of KrakenD 1.2. You can get it packaged from the download page.
Some of the highlights include:
Added a /__health endpoint Removed the wording whitelist and blacklist from all our products (#BlackLivesMatter) Datadog integration Array manipulation available after merging multiple backends KRAKEND_-like environment vars to override configuration A lot of small features and bugfixes Summary of changes KrakenD 1.2.0 adds a health endpoint, array manipulation, safejson encoding, Datadog integration, JWT claims as url parameters, and many other features and bugfixes.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD 1.1 with Kafka integration released</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-1.1-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-1.1-release-notes/</guid><description>The KrakenD team is pleased to announce the release of KrakenD 1.1. You can get it packaged from the download page.
Some of the highlights include:
Kafka integration Extended Docker image Added Telemetry for Azure Monitor More performance improvements Summary of changes KrakenD 1.1.0 adds Kafka integration, an extended Docker image, telemetry for Azure Monitor and performance improvements.
Corrected a bug in the httpsecure module. Lambda context as base64 json-encoded context Lua request and response helpers Upgraded to Go 1.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD 1.0 announcement</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/announcing-krakend-1.0/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/announcing-krakend-1.0/</guid><description>In November 2016, we released KrakenD framework to the public. Today, after three years serving traffic around the world, and a lot of lessons learned on the way, KrakenD 1.0 is out 🎉🎉🎉
KrakenD 1.0 is our announcement to the world that our libraries are now fully established and with the solid commitment of keeping backward compatibility. In the last twelve months, we have seen 120,000+ clusters in the world and 1M+ docker pulls, but as we always did (since 0.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD 0.9 released</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-0.9-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-0.9-release-notes/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been only one month since we released KrakenD 0.8, and although we have been releasing new versions approximately every 3 months, we have very interesting features that can&amp;rsquo;t wait! KrakenD 0.9 comes with a series of very demanded features. Let&amp;rsquo;s get started!
Integration with AMQP The AMQP integration allows you to send and receive messages to and from a queue through the KrakenD API Gateway. This feature enables the gateway to become in both a subscriber and a consumer of messages for asynchronous processing and opens the doors to very different implementations we were seeing.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD 0.8 released</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-0.8-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-0.8-release-notes/</guid><description>KrakenD 0.8 is a significant release as it brings numerous code changes and functionality. The framework brings +100 commits, the gateway +50 commits and even more changes in the components. A lot of refactoring and component updates has taken place. The big picture is a move from a single binary application to become a package with several internal binaries.
See the details below.
KrakenD framework The KrakenD framework brings +100 commits compared to 0.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD 0.7 released</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-0.7-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-0.7-release-notes/</guid><description>The most relevant features for the 0.7 release are increased metrics and tracing options, and functionality that has been requested by many, the sequential proxy merger. During this release, we also updated the KrakenD brand with a new logo, and we added more documentation.
On the metrics side, we can now send structured events using GELF to your Graylog Cluster. Opencensus middleware adds new functionality to push metrics to your Google StackDriver account.</description></item><item><title>Krakend 0.6.1 release notes</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-0.6.1-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 09:15:49 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-0.6.1-release-notes/</guid><description>The 0.6.1 release adds TLS and enables HTTP2 and HTTPS.
TL;DR This release brings HTTP2 and HTTPS to KrakenD. It also upgrades Go from 1.10 to 1.11 and fixes forwarded query string parameters to backends that are using arrays and repeated variables.
The KrakenDesigner (UI) is also updated to reflect these changes.
KrakenD framework The KrakenD framework has the following relevant changes:
NEW: Added support for HTTP2/HTTPS FIX: query string parameters works now with arrays and repeated variables (e.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD 0.6 autumn release</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-0.6-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 09:18:53 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-0.6-release-notes/</guid><description>As if we were an agrarian society, our releases keep revolving around the weather calendar seasons. Autumn is around the corner (northern hemisphere), so our release is ready for a cool autumn.
TL;DR This release adds two interesting components: the JOSE component responsible for the JWT signing and validation, and the Cross-origin resource sharing (CORS) component. There is also a Consul client available.
The Krakend Playground and the KrakenDesigner (UI) is also updated.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD 0.5 summer release</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-0.5-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 14:50:53 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-0.5-release-notes/</guid><description>KrakenD 0.5 is out and we want to share some of the cool stuff this release is bringing.
This release focuses heavily on metrics and its export options to different backend systems such as Zipkin, InfluxDB, Prometheus or Jaeger. It also adds the NoOp logger and exposes all the advanced settings of the http client and server, giving all the power to the user. On the middleware side it extends even more the ecosystem with multiple components.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD 0.4 release notes</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-0.4-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2018 14:50:53 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-0.4-release-notes/</guid><description>KrakenD 0.4 materializes the announcement we did 3 months ago by going full open source and public releasing the former enterprise-only components.
This release note comprehends both the KrakenD framework and the KrakenD Community Edition binary distribution.
KrakenD framework The KrakenD framework, engine of the KrakenD API Gateway. The summary of changes introduced in the 0.4 are:
Removed ALL external dependencies and placed to krakend-contrib repositories Decoder and Service Discovery register system Response metadata Response decoder and formatter exposed Custom status code handler Minor handler optimizations Config version upgraded Server configuration extended (with timeouts and limits) Now non strict REST urls are allowed Request and response manipulation optimized func version for all the interfaces Link to 0.</description></item></channel></rss>