<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>API Throttling Guide: Control Traffic &amp; Prevent Abuse on KrakenD - Open source API Gateway</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/docs/enterprise/throttling/</link><description>Recent content in API Throttling Guide: Control Traffic &amp; Prevent Abuse on KrakenD - Open source API Gateway</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.krakend.io/docs/enterprise/throttling/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Load Balancing and Throttling in KrakenD API Gateway</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/docs/enterprise/throttling/load-balancing/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/docs/enterprise/throttling/load-balancing/</guid><description>The natural placement of an API gateway is between API consumers and your services. When we talk about load balancing, we can refer to both sides of the gateway: ingress traffic (user to gateway) or egress traffic (gateway to services).
The different load balancer placements you can have are illustrated in the image above.
Balancing ingress traffic (to KrakenD) We recommend having a few containers or servers in production to have high availability.</description></item><item><title>How API Traffic Throttling with Token Bucket algorithm works</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/docs/enterprise/throttling/token-bucket/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/docs/enterprise/throttling/token-bucket/</guid><description>The Token Bucket algorithm helps you to allow or deny requests depending on the levels of traffic you are having. The algorithm is used to offer functionalities like the Spike Arrest and the several Rate Limiting options.
A quick analogy If you ever went to a traveling carnival, funfair, or amusement park to get into the attractions, you probably exchanged money for tokens/tickets at the ticket booth. The tokens help the carousel operator, bumper cars, or chance games stand to collect the payment faster and allow or deny access.</description></item><item><title>Spike Arrest and Burst</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/docs/enterprise/throttling/spike-arrest/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/docs/enterprise/throttling/spike-arrest/</guid><description>The Spike Arrest policy ensures a minimum time between different requests. KrakenD will enable Spike Arrest after exhausting the burst capacity of the rate-limiting features.
Bursting control The bursting control is the policy that defines what to do when you reach the throttling capacity of the system within a second.
When users consume content with rate-limiting enabled, the capacity of the rate limit defines the bursting they can have. Bursting makes users have a relatively higher number of requests for a short time.</description></item><item><title>Bot Detection and Throttling Guide: Prevent API Abuse</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/docs/enterprise/throttling/botdetector/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/docs/enterprise/throttling/botdetector/</guid><description>The bot detector module checks incoming connections to the gateway to determine if a bot made them, helping you detect and reject bots carrying out scraping, content theft, and form spam.
Bots are detected by inspecting the User-Agent and comparing its value with a set of configuration rules provided by you. The bot detector module does not set any initial rules, meaning that is up to you to decide the best rules for your use case, and choose how restrictive or permissive you are with bots.</description></item><item><title>API Throttling and Timeout Management</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/docs/enterprise/throttling/timeouts/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/docs/enterprise/throttling/timeouts/</guid><description>Being KrakenD, an API Gateway that talks to other services, controlling the waiting times for different aspects is crucial. KrakenD will allow you to fine-tune these settings.
The timeouts can apply to:
The duration of the whole pipe (from user request to user response) The HTTP request related timeouts Additionally, you can control the number of maximum IDLE connections.
Default timeout The timeout key in the krakend.json at the root level is used to apply a default timeout for those endpoints that do not specify one.</description></item><item><title>Stateless Cluster Throttling: Optimize API Performance</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/docs/enterprise/throttling/cluster/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/docs/enterprise/throttling/cluster/</guid><description>The stateless rate-limiting (service Enterprise or endpoint types) is the recommended approach for almost all scenarios. As the API Gateway does not have any centralization, the limits apply individually to each running instance of KrakenD.
Global rate limit If you prefer not to use a stateless rate limit, the KrakenD Enterprise edition has a stateful Redis-backed rate limit where counters are shared amongst all nodes. Working in a cluster implies applying the limits taking into account the deployment size.</description></item><item><title>Global Rate Limiting in KrakenD API Gateway</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/docs/enterprise/throttling/global-rate-limit/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/docs/enterprise/throttling/global-rate-limit/</guid><description>The global rate limit functionality enables a Redis database store to centralize all KrakenD node counters. Instead of having each KrakenD node count its hits, the counters are global and stored in the database.
Default rate limit (stateless) vs. Global rate limit (stateful) It&amp;rsquo;s essential to understand the differences between these two antagonistic approaches, so let&amp;rsquo;s put an example.
Let&amp;rsquo;s say you have four different KrakenD nodes running in a cluster, and you want to limit a specific set of users to 100 requests per second.</description></item><item><title>IP Filtering</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/docs/enterprise/throttling/ipfilter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/docs/enterprise/throttling/ipfilter/</guid><description>The IP filtering plugin allows you to restrict the traffic to your API gateway based on the IP address. It works in two different modes (allow or deny) where you define the list of IPs (CIDR blocks) that are authorized to use the API, or that are denied from using the API.
The filtering applies globally to all endpoints, or to only specific endpoints depending on the placement of the configuration.</description></item></channel></rss>