<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Technical Insights &amp; Best Practices on KrakenD - Open source API Gateway</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/categories/technical-insights--best-practices/</link><description>Recent content in Technical Insights &amp; Best Practices on KrakenD - Open source API Gateway</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2024 20:25:33 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.krakend.io/categories/technical-insights--best-practices/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Improving The Developer Experience of Your APIs</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/improving-developer-experience-moesif-krakend/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2024 20:25:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/improving-developer-experience-moesif-krakend/</guid><description>Contributor note This is a guest post by Matt Tanner, Head of Developer Relations at Moesif, our advanced API Analytics, Governance, and Monetization partners. Matt utilizes his extensive experience to help developers and product managers optimize the Moesif platform. As a modern organization, you’re likely building many APIs. Most are exposed internally and externally, allowing developers of varying backgrounds to leverage them. Building APIs developers love to use is the key to adoption, success, and growth.</description></item><item><title>Automating License Validity Checks with KrakenD</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/automating-license-check/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 13:25:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/automating-license-check/</guid><description>KrakenD&amp;rsquo;s Enterprise Edition offers a feature for automated license validity checks. While we at KrakenD always take a proactive role in renewals and interim replacements, we understand the importance of automated systems in avoiding oversights, especially in critical components like your API gateway.
Why Monitor License Validity? Monitoring license validity is a crucial step in maintaining operational stability, particularly as your business scales. An expired license could lead to unexpected disruptions in your API gateway, a key component in your infrastructure.</description></item><item><title>From OpenCensus to OpenTelemetry</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/from-opencensus-to-opentelemetry/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 12:25:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/from-opencensus-to-opentelemetry/</guid><description>In deployments of complex, distributed, and cloud-native environments, understanding the intricacies of application behavior and performance is crucial, and this is why KrakenD integrated advanced telemetry six years ago through OpenCensus and native metrics.
With the release of KrakenD v2.6, we have created an integration for OpenTelemetry and marks a significant evolution in its observability capabilities, providing users with enhanced insights and diagnostics tools.
What are the benefits of the OTEL integration OpenTelemetry represents a pivotal shift in how telemetry data is collected and managed.</description></item><item><title>How KrakenD API Gateway uses JSON Schema</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/json-schema-use-case/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/json-schema-use-case/</guid><description>Adopting best practices in the dynamic realm of API development is critical to ensuring data integrity, security, and seamless interactions.
In our experience, JSON Schema (project website) emerged as a fundamental tool in this journey. Since we started using it, the developer experience has dramatically improved for KrakenD core developers and KrakenD users.
KrakenD uses JSON Schema mainly for five very distinct use cases (though there are more):
Validating incoming requests on runtime Ensure complete responses before returning them to users Validate configuration files in deployment and build processes.</description></item><item><title>API Response Manipulation: Enhanced Control and Flexibility</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/response-manipulation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 10:25:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/response-manipulation/</guid><description>&amp;nbsp; Table of contents Ready-to-Use Options for Response Manipulation 1. Comprehensive Manipulations: Aggregation, Filtering, Grouping, Mapping 2. Enhancing Response Manipulations with Martian 3. Enhanced Manipulation with Regular Expressions 4. Advanced Content Manipulation with a Query Language 5. Advanced Response Manipulation with Templates: Power and Versatility Extensible Options for Tailored Response Manipulation 6. Lua Scripting 7. Request / Response Custom Plugin Modifiers Conclusion: KrakenD - Power, Flexibility, and Simplicity in API Management KrakenD is a versatile tool for API management that shines in handling the complex aspects of API-based systems, and is particularly noted for its backend response manipulation.</description></item><item><title>Keep-Alive Connections And Its Critical Role While Optimizing API Performance</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/keep-alive-optimizing-performance/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 20:25:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/keep-alive-optimizing-performance/</guid><description>An important yet often overlooked aspect while optimizing API performance is the management of HTTP keep-alive connections. KrakenD, an advanced API Gateway, offers an array of configuration parameters that significantly influence these connections. This post delves into these parameters, elucidating how they affect API performance.
Understanding Keep-Alive in HTTP HTTP keep-alive is a protocol mechanism that maintains an open connection between the client and the server. It allows multiple requests and responses over a single connection, reducing the overhead of establishing new connections, thus enhancing API performance.</description></item><item><title>Enhancing KrakenD operations with complementing technologies</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/complementary-technologies/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 10:01:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/complementary-technologies/</guid><description>&amp;nbsp; Table of contents Local Development &amp;amp; Debugging Deployment &amp;amp; Orchestration Continuous Integration/Continuous Deployment (CI/CD) Load Balancing &amp;amp; Scalability Service Mesh &amp;amp; Internal Traffic Management Security / Auth Streaming, Queuing &amp;amp; Event-Driven Communication Monitoring, Visualization &amp;amp; Performance Optimization Conclusion Exploring platform architecture often highlights the potential of technology collaborations. KrakenD stands out by aligning effortlessly with a variety of specialized solutions and technical stacks, thanks to its unopinionated design approach.</description></item><item><title>Unlocking the Power of OpenAPI with KrakenD Enterprise</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/openapi-krakend-enterprise/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2023 13:25:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/openapi-krakend-enterprise/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;re in the API game, you&amp;rsquo;ve likely heard of the OpenAPI Specification (OAS). But have you ever wondered how to leverage it to its fullest potential? In this blog post, we&amp;rsquo;ll dive deep into what OpenAPI is, its key use cases, and how KrakenD Enterprise customers can harness its capabilities to streamline their API management.
What is OpenAPI? OpenAPI is a specification for building APIs. It serves as a blueprint that describes how your API works and what it can do.</description></item><item><title>Securing Sensitive Data with KrakenD API Data Masking</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/api-data-masking/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 13:25:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/api-data-masking/</guid><description>Securing sensitive data is a non-negotiable requirement for organizations. API data masking is a robust security measure that can help you achieve this. This article dives into the mechanics of API data masking and how KrakenD&amp;rsquo;s features like regex content replacer and response body generator can make this process more efficient and compliant.
Understanding API Data Masking API data masking is a technique that replaces original data with random or pseudonymous data.</description></item><item><title>The Importance of an API Gateway in Modern Services Architecture</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/importance-of-api-gateway-modern-services-architecture/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 13:25:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/importance-of-api-gateway-modern-services-architecture/</guid><description>How KrakenD Steers the Fleet As we traverse the evolving landscape of modern services architecture, the significance of an API Gateway cannot be overstated. At KrakenD, we are not just participating in this evolution but leading it. We have channeled our expertise into developing an API Gateway solution that is efficient, scalable, and perfectly tuned to meet the specific needs of the digital age.
What is an API Gateway? Think of an API Gateway as the touchpoint that connects your clients to your backend services.</description></item><item><title>REST vs gRPC vs GraphQL in KrakenD: A Comprehensive Comparison</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/rest-grpc-graphql-krakend-comparison/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 13:25:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/rest-grpc-graphql-krakend-comparison/</guid><description>Understanding the landscape of APIs and making the right choice can seem daunting, especially with a myriad of available technologies. This is where KrakenD, your trusted partner in API management, steps in. We offer an in-depth comparison of three leading technologies: REST, gRPC, and GraphQL, examining their strengths, drawbacks, and how they integrate with KrakenD.
REST: The Reliable Partner Enhanced by KrakenD REST (Representational State Transfer) is a time-tested, reliable technology in the API world.</description></item><item><title>Modernizing your legacy SOAP services with KrakenD</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/modernizing-soap-services/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/modernizing-soap-services/</guid><description>We are thrilled to introduce one of our latest features: SOAP integration. This powerful integration is designed to help businesses modernize their legacy SOAP systems without the need for extensive modifications.
Understanding SOAP and Its Limitations SOAP (Simple Object Access Protocol) is a protocol specification for exchanging structured information in web services using XML. It operates over HTTP for simplicity and compatibility, but also supports other protocols such as SMTP. SOAP&amp;rsquo;s primary application is in large-scale enterprise environments with high security and transactional requirements.</description></item><item><title>Step-by-step Migration Guide: From AWS API Gateway to KrakenD API Gateway</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/migrate-aws-api-gateway-to-krakend/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 13:25:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/migrate-aws-api-gateway-to-krakend/</guid><description>Introduction As you consider migrating from AWS API Gateway to KrakenD API Gateway, you&amp;rsquo;re likely driven by a number of compelling benefits such as a better pricing model, reduced vendor lock-in, operational simplicity, enhanced content manipulation and transformation capabilities, increased connectivity protocols, and extensibility trough Custom golang Plugins or Lua scripts. This guide will walk you through the primary steps and considerations in this migration process.
Pre-Migration Before starting the migration process, it&amp;rsquo;s essential to make sure to map your existing API Gateway resources to equivalent KrakenD concepts, which include endpoints, routers, and backends.</description></item><item><title>Understanding API Calls: The KrakenD Approach</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/api-calls/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 13:25:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/api-calls/</guid><description>KrakenD, a market leader in high-performance API Gateway solutions, enables seamless and efficient API interactions within today&amp;rsquo;s complex digital landscape. This comprehensive guide delves into the intricate details of API calls and their pivotal role within the microservices architecture, specifically in a KrakenD environment.
Understanding API Calls: The Essence of Software Interactions APIs, or Application Programming Interfaces, form the core of sophisticated software interactions, providing the pathways for communication between different software modules.</description></item><item><title>Optimize you API Gateway Management with Flexible Configuration</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/unleash-power-flexible-configuration/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/unleash-power-flexible-configuration/</guid><description>Flexible Configuration is a template-based configuration system for KrakenD API Gateway that allows you to manage configurations efficiently and cater to multiple environments. In this blog post, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore the pain-points it addresses and the benefits it brings to customers.
Challenges solved by Flexible Configuration Organizing and managing configurations can be challenging, especially when:
Configurations are extensive and need to be split into multiple files You need to inject environment-specific variables Reusable code blocks and placeholders are necessary to avoid repetition Multiple developers are working on the API gateway KrakenD is managed using multiple repositories Tracking changes, avoiding conflicts, and reviewing code is crucial Flexible Configuration is designed to tackle these pain-points effectively.</description></item><item><title>Benefits of a Stateless API Gateway</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/benefits-of-stateless-api-gateway/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/benefits-of-stateless-api-gateway/</guid><description>API Gateways play a crucial role in modern software architecture, enabling developers to manage and route traffic between client applications and backend services. KrakenD stands out due to its stateless design, which provides several significant advantages over other solutions.
What is a Stateless API Gateway? A stateless API Gateway is an APII Gateway that doesn&amp;rsquo;t depend on a centralized database for storing configurations or maintaining a shared &amp;ldquo;state.&amp;rdquo; Instead, each instance of the API Gateway possesses its own configuration file, read when the service initiates.</description></item><item><title>Traffic mirroring: test APIs without tests</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-shadow-testing/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-shadow-testing/</guid><description>Integration and load testing are in the list of best practices in our sector, but synthesizing good inputs for such tests and analyzing the results are usually two hard things to achieve. This post will show you how we suggest our customers set up a shadow testing system with minimal impact on the production environment and proper harness.
Quick overview As pointed out at https://cloud.google.com/architecture/application-deployment-and-testing-strategies
Testing new backend features by using the production load.</description></item><item><title>Building a Telemetry Service</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/building-a-telemetry-service/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 09:40:25 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/building-a-telemetry-service/</guid><description>​ We have run our telemetry system live for the past three years now. In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll share code and outline some of the things you&amp;rsquo;ll need to keep in mind if you want to build an anonymous usage reporting system for an open-source project as we did (at a ridiculous cost).
We will show you how to use our reporting client and the details of our actual reporting servers in case you are thinking in implementing a cost-efficient solution with high scalability.</description></item><item><title>Doing housekeeping on your configuration file</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/housekeeping-configuration-file/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/housekeeping-configuration-file/</guid><description>Starting your krakend.json configuration from scratch and writing every attribute in a blank editor might be a difficult and time consuming task, and that&amp;rsquo;s why we have the KrakenDesigner.
KrakenDesigner is an aid tool to generate KrakenD configurations for the uninitiated audience. It produces a verbose output of the configuration file and explicitly writes unneeded attributes to let you see that a specific configuration option exists. These attributes I am mentioning are not necessary because they contain default values and the server is not going to alter its behavior.</description></item><item><title>How we run KrakenD on Javascript with WebAssembly</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-wasm/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-wasm/</guid><description>KrakenD is an API Gateway written in Go that uses a single configuration file to define its whole behavior. As the configuration file might be complicated, the KrakenDesigner is a javascript-based user interface to edit this file, and we were missing the capability of reproducing directly on javascript the existing gateway pipes so that users could run manual tests over the editing configuration.
In this post, we are going to explain how we included KrakenD framework components in a .</description></item><item><title>Website development as a sysadmin</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/website-development-as-a-sysadmin/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2018 16:18:25 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/website-development-as-a-sysadmin/</guid><description>As a systems administrator for the past 15 years, I&amp;rsquo;m not very used to web development as this kind of work has been usually done by other colleagues in every company I&amp;rsquo;ve worked for. I wanted to create a web application myself using an external API, as an exercise to go out my comfort zone.
Some time ago I found that Marvel Comics has a REST API where you can get a lot of information about comics, characters, authors and other interesting information.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD Golang Plugins - Extending the Functionality</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-golang-plugins/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 22:07:03 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-golang-plugins/</guid><description>The release of golang 1.8 more than a year ago opened the door to loading dynamic linked components in run time, and we were keen to find out if we could include this great feature in our KrakenD toolbox.
We&amp;rsquo;d like to share our experience and details on how we enhanced our products to support golang plugins.
Why would anyone use plugins in Go? The plugin concept is widely known and supported in several programming languages and environments.</description></item><item><title>Deploying and versioning an API Gateway</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/deploying-an-api-gateway/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 23:46:25 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/deploying-an-api-gateway/</guid><description>When it comes to maintaining and deploying an API Gateway within an organization, you should always be aware of best practice. A gateway is an extra step between the client and the servers with the power to define a whole new interface, yet it&amp;rsquo;s so flexible and easy to implement that you might be tempted to start creating API interfaces without thinking about it - and end up creating problems for the future.</description></item><item><title>An API Gateway is not the new Unicorn</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/what-is-an-api-gateway/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 10:10:53 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/what-is-an-api-gateway/</guid><description>The more we talk to people about API gateways, the more we have come to realize that the term means different things to different people, and more specifically we see a growing trend where developers (but mostly managers) expect an API gateway to be able to perform miracles, usually a long way away from its intended use.
It&amp;rsquo;s as if the API Gateway is the new unicorn that will solve all problems and make everything wonderful in the microservices scene.</description></item><item><title>Automating Linux Packaging for KrakenD API Gateway</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/automating-linux-packaging/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2017 12:43:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/automating-linux-packaging/</guid><description>Everyone loves reaching the maximum number of available platforms for their software but this usually comes at a cost. In this article we will explain how we generated our packaging for Linux in an automated fashion, being faithful to our DevOps dogma.
Dockerize all the things! Our dev team uses both Linux and MacOS X in desktop machines and KrakenD has been running and behaving in the same way in all the platforms because from day one we decided to run everything on Docker.</description></item></channel></rss>