<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Golang on KrakenD API Gateway</title>
    <link>https://www.krakend.io/tags/golang/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Golang on KrakenD API Gateway</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.krakend.io/tags/golang/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How we run KrakenD on Javascript with WebAssembly</title>
      <link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-wasm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-wasm/</guid>
      <description>KrakenD is an API Gateway written in Go that uses a single configuration file to define its whole behavior. As the configuration file might be complicated, the KrakenDesigner is a javascript-based user interface to edit this file, and we were missing the capability of reproducing directly on javascript the existing gateway pipes so that users could run manual tests over the editing configuration.
In this post, we are going to explain how we included KrakenD framework components in a .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running the KrakenD API Gateway on Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-on-kubernetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2018 18:47:03 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-on-kubernetes/</guid>
      <description>In this article we are going to show how to configure and deploy the KrakenD API Gateway in a kubernetes environment.
We will use for the demonstration Minikube so you cant test it in your own local machine.
Let&amp;rsquo;s get started!
Setting up a local Kubernetes We will run Kubernetes locally thanks to Minikube. Just follow the README in the project for the installation and the Quickstart section. Installing minikube it&amp;rsquo;s quick and easy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Website development as a sysadmin</title>
      <link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/website-development-as-a-sysadmin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2018 16:18:25 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/website-development-as-a-sysadmin/</guid>
      <description>As a systems administrator for the past 15 years, I&amp;rsquo;m not very used to web development as this kind of work has been usually done by other colleagues in every company I&amp;rsquo;ve worked for. I wanted to create a web application myself using an external API, as an exercise to go out my comfort zone.
Some time ago I found that Marvel Comics has a REST API where you can get a lot of information about comics, characters, authors and other interesting information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to work with Golang plugins and KrakenD</title>
      <link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-golang-plugins/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 22:07:03 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-golang-plugins/</guid>
      <description>The release of golang 1.8 more than a year ago opened the door to loading dynamic linked components in run time, and we were keen to find out if we could include this great feature in our KrakenD toolbox.
We&amp;rsquo;d like to share our experience and details on how we enhanced our products to support golang plugins.
Why would anyone use plugins in Go? The plugin concept is widely known and supported in several programming languages and environments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying and versioning an API Gateway</title>
      <link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/deploying-an-api-gateway/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 23:46:25 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/deploying-an-api-gateway/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to maintaining and deploying an API Gateway within an organization, you should always be aware of best practice. A gateway is an extra step between the client and the servers with the power to define a whole new interface, yet it&amp;rsquo;s so flexible and easy to implement that you might be tempted to start creating API interfaces without thinking about it - and end up creating problems for the future.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>