<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Configuration on KrakenD - Open source API Gateway</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/categories/configuration/</link><description>Recent content in Configuration on KrakenD - Open source API Gateway</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.krakend.io/categories/configuration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Doing housekeeping on your KrakenD configuration file</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/housekeeping-configuration-file/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/housekeeping-configuration-file/</guid><description>Starting your krakend.json configuration from scratch and writing every attribute in a blank editor might be a difficult and time consuming task, and that&amp;rsquo;s why we have the KrakenDesigner.
KrakenDesigner is an aid tool to generate KrakenD configurations for the uninitiated audience. It produces a verbose output of the configuration file and explicitly writes unneeded attributes to let you see that a specific configuration option exists. These attributes I am mentioning are not necessary because they contain default values and the server is not going to alter its behavior.</description></item><item><title>Reloading the Krakend configuration with Reflex and Docker</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/reloading-the-krakend-configuration/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 11:06:53 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/reloading-the-krakend-configuration/</guid><description>Read the new documentation This is an article from 2018. You might want to see the Hot reload documentation. A recurrent question when we go around is if KrakenD configuration can be hot-reloaded, this is changing endpoints, backends, or any other configuration of the gateway while it&amp;rsquo;s running. The short answer is: No, you can&amp;rsquo;t. You must restart the server. And although we might have something to alleviate this, let us explain first why we don&amp;rsquo;t support such a feature:</description></item></channel></rss>