<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>KrakenD Community Edition Documentation on KrakenD - Open source API Gateway</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/docs/v2.11/overview/</link><description>Recent content in KrakenD Community Edition Documentation on KrakenD - Open source API Gateway</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.krakend.io/docs/v2.11/overview/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>KrakenD API Gateway Installation Guide</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/docs/v2.11/overview/installing/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/docs/v2.11/overview/installing/</guid><description>KrakenD is a single binary file that does not require any external libraries to work. To install KrakenD choose your operative system in the downloads section or use the Docker image.
Download Generate a config file Installation You can install (or just run) KrakenD using different options. Just exploring? Use the KrakenD Playground if you want to play with KrakenD without configuring it. The Playground comes with several flavors of KrakenD and a mock API.</description></item><item><title>Running KrakenD server</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/docs/v2.11/overview/run/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/docs/v2.11/overview/run/</guid><description>After installing KrakenD, you can start using KrakenD by typing krakend. To see all the options of krakend, type krakend -h or krakend &amp;lt;COMMAND&amp;gt; -h. For instance, the krakend run help is:
Run command help&amp;nbsp; $krakend run -h ╓▄█ ▄▄▌ ╓██████▄µ ▐███ ▄███╨▐███▄██H╗██████▄ ║██▌ ,▄███╨ ▄██████▄ ▓██▌█████▄ ███▀╙╙▀▀███╕ ▐███▄███▀ ▐█████▀&amp;#34;╙▀▀&amp;#34;╙▀███ ║███▄███┘ ███▀&amp;#34;&amp;#34;▀███ ████▀╙▀███H ███ ╙███ ▐██████▌ ▐███⌐ ,▄████████M║██████▄ ║██████████M███▌ ███H ███ ,███ ▐███╨▀███µ ▐███ ███▌ ,███M║███╙▀███ ███▄```▄▄` ███▌ ███H ███,,,╓▄███▀ ▐███ ╙███▄▐███ ╙█████████M║██▌ ╙███▄`▀███████╨ ███▌ ███H █████████▀ `` `&amp;#39;` Version: 2.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD API Gateway Playground</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/docs/v2.11/overview/playground/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/docs/v2.11/overview/playground/</guid><description>If you are new to KrakenD, a quick way to get started is to make use of the KrakenD Playground.
The KrakenD Playground is a Docker Compose environment that puts together the necessary pieces to let you play with KrakenD in a working environment.
As KrakenD is an API gateway, we have also added to the environment an API (backend) to feed the gateway and a website to make use of the data.</description></item><item><title>Lura vs. KrakenD</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/docs/v2.11/overview/lura-vs-krakend/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/docs/v2.11/overview/lura-vs-krakend/</guid><description>If you had a quick look at our git repositories or the documentation, you might be confused at first, as there is something called the Lura Project and also KrakenD.
TL;DR; Difference between Lura, KrakenD, and Enterprise Lura is the KrakenD&amp;rsquo;s engine. Formerly known as &amp;ldquo;KrakenD framework&amp;rdquo; until we donated it to The Linux Foundation on 2021. It is not a product itself but a toolkit/set of libraries to build API gateways.</description></item><item><title>Comprehensive Guides for KrakenD API Gateway</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/docs/v2.11/overview/guides/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/docs/v2.11/overview/guides/</guid><description>The documentation in this site covers all the functionality of KrakenD API Gateway, but over time we have received from KrakenD users all kinds of tutorials, guides and other resources that illustrate how to do a specific thing. We have included below a few links, but you can share yours.
Add a link User-contributed resources Getting started with KrakenD on Kubernetes / AKS by Christian Dennig (Cloud Solution Architect @ Microsoft) Build and Deploy with Kubernetes, Helm, and Skaffold by Fabijan Bajo (Technical Lead, DevOps / Cloud Infrastructure @ IBM) Microservices with Micronaut, KrakenD and Consul by Piotr Minkowski (Solution Architect @ Red Hat) How to Successfully Set Up KrakenD on GKE: A Step by Step Guide by Vijay Savanth on Hackernoon Writing Plugins using Golang by Ilya Nemtsev on Eventslooped Building Micro Services with .</description></item><item><title>Verifying packages (PGP and SHA256)</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/docs/v2.11/overview/verifying-packages/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/docs/v2.11/overview/verifying-packages/</guid><description>How to make sure what you are downloading is legit.
PGP We will check the detached signature PGP against our package KrakenD.
Term&amp;nbsp; $gpg --verify krakend_2.11_amd64_generic-linux.tar.gz.asc krakend_2.11_amd64_generic-linux.tar.gz gpg: Signature made Sun Mar 10 18:17:18 2019 UTC using RSA key ID 5DE6FD698AD6FDD2 gpg: Can&amp;#39;t check signature: public key not found We don&amp;rsquo;t have the packager public key (AB39BEA1) in our system. You need to retrieve the public key from a key server.</description></item></channel></rss>