<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blogs on KrakenD - Open source API Gateway</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blogs on KrakenD - Open source API Gateway</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.krakend.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>KrakenD framework becomes a Linux Foundation project</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-framework-joins-the-linux-foundation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-framework-joins-the-linux-foundation/</guid><description>Today, together with the Linux Foundation, we are announcing that the KrakenD framework, our core engine, has been donated to the Linux Foundation and is now the &amp;ldquo;Lura Project.&amp;quot;
The Lura Project&amp;rsquo;s mission is to offer an extendable, simple, and stateless high-performance API Gateway framework designed for cloud-native and on-prem setups. Rather than solving a specific use case, Lura provides a library of components, a framework for assembling them into custom API gateway systems like a Lego set.</description></item><item><title>Albert Garcia to expand KrakenD business.</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/albert-garcia-expand-krakend-business/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/albert-garcia-expand-krakend-business/</guid><description>Today, we are announcing that Albert Garcia recently joined KrakenD as Director of Business Development and member of the Board.
In his role, he will identify and develop new business opportunities to help expand even more the presence of KrakenD. Garcia will spearhead new markets and emerging trends, sales, and client relationship management, to name a few.
Having worked previously with him for more than 15 years, we know that Garcia is the right person at the right time for KrakenD.</description></item><item><title>How we built our telemetry service</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/building-a-telemetry-service/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 09:40:25 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/building-a-telemetry-service/</guid><description>​ We have run our telemetry system live for the past three years now. In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll share code and outline some of the things you&amp;rsquo;ll need to keep in mind if you want to build an anonymous usage reporting system for an open-source project as we did at a ridiculous cost.
We have an activity of 700,000 reporting servers/month with a monthly cost betwen 5 and 10 EUR ($12).</description></item><item><title>KrakenD 1.3.0 released</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-1.3-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-1.3-release-notes/</guid><description>The KrakenD team is pleased to announce the release of KrakenD 1.3.0. You can get it packaged from the download page.
KrakenD 1.3.0 makes focus on completing the RBAC system regarding JWT. The main highlights are:
JWT: Complete the RBAC system and flexibility improvements:
Scopes validation (thanks to @chrisdennig) Extract and forward claims as headers (thanks to @chrisdennig) Support for Oracle Identity Cloud Service by allowing key identifers other than kid such as x5t or kid_x5t (contribution from Oracle) Allow loading of local JWK files Integration with secret providers such as: Amazon KMS Azure&amp;rsquo;s Key Vault Google Cloud KMS Hashicorp&amp;rsquo;s Vault Encrypted or plain base64 file Other features:</description></item><item><title>KrakenD partners with Microsoft to distribute in Azure</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-partners-with-microsoft/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-partners-with-microsoft/</guid><description>KrakenD continues to expand its distribution channels and services by partnering with Microsoft to publish its API Gateway on Azure Marketplace.
As a first step, the Azure Marketplace now counts with a ready-to-use KrakenD image for the open-source edition that helps users of the Azure Kubernete Service (AKS) to quickly and securely publish services through KrakenD API Gateway.
According to a Cloud Solution Architect at Microsoft KrakenD is a great fit in the cloud-native space and a recommended product for AKS workloads and Kubernetes in general</description></item><item><title>KrakenD 1.2.0 released</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-1.2-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-1.2-release-notes/</guid><description>The KrakenD team is pleased to announce the release of KrakenD 1.2. You can get it packaged from the download page.
Some of the highlights include:
Added a /__health endpoint Removed the wording whitelist and blacklist from all our products (#BlackLivesMatter) Datadog integration Array manipulation available after merging multiple backends KRAKEND_-like environment vars to override configuration A lot of small features and bugfixes KrakenD framework Summary of the most significant changes:</description></item><item><title>KrakenD Usage Stats - March 2020</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/usage-stats-march-2020/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/usage-stats-march-2020/</guid><description>KrakenD servers with telemetry enabled help us to understand the usage of KrakenD in production. Last month we witnessed 356K running instances, and we wanted to share some data with you. 👇
From mid-March, we have seen an exciting increase in the number of KrakenD instances seen per day: x12! The trend is just beautiful, including the cumulative.
According to our internal definition, an instance is every time a KrakenD is started.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD 1.1 with Kafka integration released</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-1.1-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-1.1-release-notes/</guid><description>The KrakenD team is pleased to announce the release of KrakenD 1.1. You can get it packaged from the download page.
Some of the highlights include:
Kafka integration Extended Docker image Added Telemetry for Azure Monitor More performance improvements Kafka integration From now on, users of Apache Kafka can publish and subscribe from KrakenD. The Kafka integration saves you from writing application logic to interact with the streaming platform and let the gateway be an active player in the event architecture pattern.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD 1.0 announcement</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/announcing-krakend-1.0/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/announcing-krakend-1.0/</guid><description>In November 2016, we released KrakenD framework to the public. Today, after three years serving traffic around the world, and a lot of lessons learned on the way, KrakenD 1.0 is out 🎉🎉🎉
KrakenD 1.0 is our announcement to the world that our libraries are now fully established and with the solid commitment of keeping backward compatibility. In the last twelve months, we have seen 120,000+ clusters in the world and 1M+ docker pulls, but as we always did (since 0.</description></item><item><title>gRPC-gateway as a KrakenD plugin</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-grpc-gateway-plugin/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2019 18:26:10 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-grpc-gateway-plugin/</guid><description>The gRPC protocol is becoming trendy in the era of microservices. Its compactness and backward-compatibility make it very attractive. However, it requires custom code to work with it. In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll show you how to get all the benefits from the gRPC protocol and the gRPC-gateway without coding any business logic to use your gRPC services as regular backends. Moreover, avoiding the extra network hop!</description></item><item><title>Doing housekeeping on your KrakenD configuration file</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/housekeeping-configuration-file/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/housekeeping-configuration-file/</guid><description>Starting your krakend.json configuration from scratch and writing every attribute in a blank editor might be a difficult and time consuming task, and that&amp;rsquo;s why we have the KrakenDesigner.
KrakenDesigner is an aid tool to generate KrakenD configurations for the uninitiated audience. It produces a verbose output of the configuration file and explicitly writes unneeded attributes to let you see that a specific configuration option exists. These attributes I am mentioning are not necessary because they contain default values and the server is not going to alter its behavior.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD 0.9 released</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-0.9-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-0.9-release-notes/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been only one month since we released KrakenD 0.8, and although we have been releasing new versions approximately every 3 months, we have very interesting features that can&amp;rsquo;t wait! KrakenD 0.9 comes with a series of very demanded features. Let&amp;rsquo;s get started!
Integration with AMQP The AMQP integration allows you to send and receive messages to and from a queue through the KrakenD API Gateway. This feature enables the gateway to become in both a subscriber and a consumer of messages for asynchronous processing and opens the doors to very different implementations we were seeing.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD 0.8 released</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-0.8-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-0.8-release-notes/</guid><description>KrakenD 0.8 is a significant release as it brings numerous code changes and functionality. The framework brings +100 commits, the gateway +50 commits and even more changes in the components. A lot of refactoring and component updates has taken place. The big picture is a move from a single binary application to become a package with several internal binaries.
See the details below.
KrakenD framework The KrakenD framework brings +100 commits compared to 0.</description></item><item><title>How we run KrakenD on Javascript with WebAssembly</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-wasm/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-wasm/</guid><description>KrakenD is an API Gateway written in Go that uses a single configuration file to define its whole behavior. As the configuration file might be complicated, the KrakenDesigner is a javascript-based user interface to edit this file, and we were missing the capability of reproducing directly on javascript the existing gateway pipes so that users could run manual tests over the editing configuration.
In this post, we are going to explain how we included KrakenD framework components in a .</description></item><item><title>KrakenD 0.7 released</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-0.7-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-0.7-release-notes/</guid><description>The most relevant features for the 0.7 release are increased metrics and tracing options, and functionality that has been requested by many, the sequential proxy merger. During this release, we also updated the KrakenD brand with a new logo, and we added more documentation.
On the metrics side, we can now send structured events using GELF to your Graylog Cluster. Opencensus middleware adds new functionality to push metrics to your Google StackDriver account.</description></item><item><title>Krakend 0.6.1 release notes</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-0.6.1-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 09:15:49 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-0.6.1-release-notes/</guid><description>The 0.6.1 release adds TLS and enables HTTP2 and HTTPS.
TL;DR This release brings HTTP2 and HTTPS to KrakenD. It also upgrades Go from 1.10 to 1.11 and fixes forwarded query string parameters to backends that are using arrays and repeated variables.
The KrakenDesigner (UI) is also updated to reflect these changes.
KrakenD framework The KrakenD framework has the following relevant changes:
NEW: Added support for HTTP2/HTTPS FIX: query string parameters works now with arrays and repeated variables (e.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD 0.6 autumn release</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-0.6-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 09:18:53 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-0.6-release-notes/</guid><description>As if we were an agrarian society, our releases keep revolving around the weather calendar seasons. Autumn is around the corner (northern hemisphere), so our release is ready for a cool autumn.
TL;DR This release adds two interesting components: the JOSE component responsible for the JWT signing and validation, and the Cross-origin resource sharing (CORS) component. There is also a Consul client available.
The Krakend Playground and the KrakenDesigner (UI) is also updated.</description></item><item><title>Reloading the Krakend configuration with Reflex and Docker</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/reloading-the-krakend-configuration/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 11:06:53 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/reloading-the-krakend-configuration/</guid><description>A recurrent question when we go around is if KrakenD configuration can be hot-reloaded, this is changing endpoints, backends, or any other configuration of the gateway while it&amp;rsquo;s running. The short answer is: No, you can&amp;rsquo;t. You must restart the server. And although we might have something to alleviate this, let us explain first why we don&amp;rsquo;t support such a feature:
Performance: This is the #1 reason, and strong enough.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD 0.5 summer release</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-0.5-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 14:50:53 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-0.5-release-notes/</guid><description>KrakenD 0.5 is out and we want to share some of the cool stuff this release is bringing.
This release focuses heavily on metrics and its export options to different backend systems such as Zipkin, InfluxDB, Prometheus or Jaeger. It also adds the NoOp logger and exposes all the advanced settings of the http client and server, giving all the power to the user. On the middleware side it extends even more the ecosystem with multiple components.</description></item><item><title>Running the KrakenD API Gateway on Kubernetes</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-on-kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2018 18:47:03 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-on-kubernetes/</guid><description>In this article we are going to show how to configure and deploy the KrakenD API Gateway in a kubernetes environment.
We will use for the demonstration Minikube so you cant test it in your own local machine.
Let&amp;rsquo;s get started!
Setting up a local Kubernetes We will run Kubernetes locally thanks to Minikube. Just follow the README in the project for the installation and the Quickstart section. Installing minikube it&amp;rsquo;s quick and easy.</description></item><item><title>Website development as a sysadmin</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/website-development-as-a-sysadmin/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2018 16:18:25 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/website-development-as-a-sysadmin/</guid><description>As a systems administrator for the past 15 years, I&amp;rsquo;m not very used to web development as this kind of work has been usually done by other colleagues in every company I&amp;rsquo;ve worked for. I wanted to create a web application myself using an external API, as an exercise to go out my comfort zone.
Some time ago I found that Marvel Comics has a REST API where you can get a lot of information about comics, characters, authors and other interesting information.</description></item><item><title>Edge computing - A story of buses, raspberries, IoT and API gateways</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-on-raspberry/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 21:25:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-on-raspberry/</guid><description>The IoT industry has been running for some years now adding millions of devices into the network. The range of devices and capabilities is very wide and heterogeneous, from small devices powered with a 9-volt battery to track the location of freight shippings traveling the oceans (using platforms like Sigfox) to permanently plugged devices with more powerful computing like a Raspberry Pi where computation cycles are not a problem.
Generally speaking, all these devices collect raw data and send it to the cloud where big data centers process it.</description></item><item><title>How to work with Golang plugins and KrakenD</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-golang-plugins/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 22:07:03 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-golang-plugins/</guid><description>The release of golang 1.8 more than a year ago opened the door to loading dynamic linked components in run time, and we were keen to find out if we could include this great feature in our KrakenD toolbox.
We&amp;rsquo;d like to share our experience and details on how we enhanced our products to support golang plugins.
Why would anyone use plugins in Go? The plugin concept is widely known and supported in several programming languages and environments.</description></item><item><title>Deploying and versioning an API Gateway</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/deploying-an-api-gateway/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 23:46:25 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/deploying-an-api-gateway/</guid><description>When it comes to maintaining and deploying an API Gateway within an organization, you should always be aware of best practice. A gateway is an extra step between the client and the servers with the power to define a whole new interface, yet it&amp;rsquo;s so flexible and easy to implement that you might be tempted to start creating API interfaces without thinking about it - and end up creating problems for the future.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD 0.4 release notes</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-0.4-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2018 14:50:53 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-0.4-release-notes/</guid><description>KrakenD 0.4 materializes the announcement we did 3 months ago by going full open source and public releasing the former enterprise-only components.
This release note comprehends both the KrakenD framework and the KrakenD Community Edition binary distribution.
KrakenD framework The KrakenD framework, engine of the KrakenD API Gateway. The summary of changes introduced in the 0.4 are:
Removed ALL external dependencies and placed to krakend-contrib repositories Decoder and Service Discovery register system Response metadata Response decoder and formatter exposed Custom status code handler Minor handler optimizations Config version upgraded Server configuration extended (with timeouts and limits) Now non strict REST urls are allowed Request and response manipulation optimized func version for all the interfaces Link to 0.</description></item><item><title>An API Gateway is not the new Unicorn</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/what-is-an-api-gateway/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 10:10:53 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/what-is-an-api-gateway/</guid><description>The more we talk to people about API gateways, the more we have come to realize that the term means different things to different people, and more specifically we see a growing trend where developers (but mostly managers) expect an API gateway to be able to perform miracles, usually a long way away from its intended use.
It&amp;rsquo;s as if the API Gateway is the new unicorn that will solve all problems and make everything wonderful in the microservices scene.</description></item><item><title>Road to KrakenD 0.4</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/road-to-0.4/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2017 12:10:53 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/road-to-0.4/</guid><description>The next iteration of KrakenD is right around the corner and the Devops Faith team and the rest of the community we are working together to launch the 0.4 release before end of year. The jump from the 0.3.9 of the binary and the 0.3 of the framework to the 0.4 will bring a lot of interesting stuff but we also need to do a remarkable change in the code for a brighter future: kill external dependencies with fire.</description></item><item><title>How we automated our RPM and DEB packaging with Docker</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/automating-linux-packaging/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2017 12:43:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/automating-linux-packaging/</guid><description>Everyone loves reaching the maximum number of available platforms for their software but this usually comes at a cost. In this article we will explain how we generated our packaging for Linux in an automated fashion, being faithful to our DevOps dogma.
Dockerize all the things! Our team uses both Ubuntu and MacOS X in desktop machines and KrakenD has been running and behaving in the same way in all the platforms because from day one we decided to run everything on Docker.</description></item><item><title>Open sourcing all enterprise components</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/open-sourcing-enterprise-features/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2017 19:01:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/open-sourcing-enterprise-features/</guid><description>What are known today as the KrakenD Enterprise components will be disclosed in the form of open source repositories in the following weeks, and the action has already started, don&amp;rsquo;t miss it! In this post we will explain the reasons behind this decision that might sound crazy from a business perspective in the first place. Why anyone would publish the paid software increment bits of an existing free software?
A look back&amp;hellip; If you are reading this post chances are that you know this already, in short KrakenD is the fastest API Gateway in the market.</description></item></channel></rss>