<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>KrakenD API Gateway Blog - Latest Updates and Insights on KrakenD - Open source API Gateway</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/</link><description>Recent content in KrakenD API Gateway Blog - Latest Updates and Insights on KrakenD - Open source API Gateway</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 11:02:12 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.krakend.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>New Look, Same Vision: KrakenD’s Website Redesign</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/new-look-same-vision/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 11:02:12 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/new-look-same-vision/</guid><description>At KrakenD, we’re excited to introduce our new website design! While our logo and core branding remain consistent, the visual overhaul gives a fresh, modern look that better conveys what KrakenD is all about. We’ve focused on a style that highlights our core principles: simplicity, high performance, and efficiency. The new design doesn’t just look better: it helps users quickly grasp KrakenD’s added value and how our solutions can simplify their API management.</description></item><item><title>Why Rate Limiting Matters for Your API’s Health and Security</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/effective-rate-limiting-traffic-management/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 09:25:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/effective-rate-limiting-traffic-management/</guid><description>When deploying APIs, rate limiting is one of the most critical strategies for managing traffic and ensuring system security. In this blog, we’ll dive into the fundamentals of API rate limiting and how platforms like KrakenD can help you implement scalable and robust rate-limiting mechanisms. Let’s explore the essentials of rate limiting and why it plays such a pivotal role in API traffic management.
What is Rate Limiting and Why is it Important?</description></item><item><title>KrakenD Partners with Massil Technologies for India and Middle East</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-partners-with-massil-technologies/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 09:25:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-partners-with-massil-technologies/</guid><description>KrakenD is pleased to announce its exclusive partnership with Massil Technologies, a leading IT services provider, as the official reseller and certified KrakenD integration partner in India and the Middle East. This strategic collaboration enhances KrakenD&amp;rsquo;s ability to provide localized API gateway solutions and support to customers across these regions.
Founded in 2016, Massil Technologies is based in Hyderabad, India, and specializes in delivering rapid IT system integrations and cloud services.</description></item><item><title>Mastering Microservices Authorization: Strategies for Secure Access Control</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/microservices-authorization-secure-access/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 09:25:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/microservices-authorization-secure-access/</guid><description>Software development has evolved significantly, and so has the way we architect applications. Microservices have emerged as a dominant pattern, offering scalability, flexibility, and resilience. The distributed nature of microservices introduces unique challenges, particularly when it comes to security. Ensuring proper authorization and access control is critical because each microservice acts as an independent unit.
In the context of microservices, access management plays a crucial role by enabling convenient authentication and authorization for both end-users and microservices.</description></item><item><title>Releases of KrakenD EE 2.7.1 and KrakenD CE 2.7.1 with minor fixes</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.7.1-ce-ee-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.7.1-ce-ee-release-notes/</guid><description>A new patch version of KrakenD Enterprise 2.7.1 and KrakenD Community 2.7.1 is now available on the download page and the Docker registry. This update addresses minor functionality and security improvements.
This release is classified as a security release due to CVE-2024-28180. The vulnerability could allow an attacker to send a JWE containing compressed data, which could consume significant memory and CPU resources when decompressed. However, KrakenD does not support JWE, so this issue is a false positive in security scans.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD EE v2.7: Workflows, enhanced Rate Limiting, Direct WS, and more</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-ee-2.7-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-ee-2.7-release-notes/</guid><description>Today, we released KrakenD EE v2.7, the latest version of our enterprise edition. This version includes many new features and enhancements to existing components. Here&amp;rsquo;s a closer look at what&amp;rsquo;s new and why it matters.
Workflows The most exciting addition in KrakenD EE v2.7 is the new workflow component that allows you to create workflows and nest virtual endpoints without limitations. This feature is a game-changer for those managing complex API ecosystems, enabling you to orchestrate multiple API calls within the gateway efficiently.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD CE v2.7 released with better rate-limiting and security options</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.7-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.7-release-notes/</guid><description>We are excited to announce the latest release of KrakenD, which focuses on resource optimization and brings new features, especially on security. Here&amp;rsquo;s a detailed look at what&amp;rsquo;s new in this release:
Finer rate-limiting We have been working on optimizing the rate-limit feature, significantly reducing the RAM consumption for users of the endpoint rate limit. Generally speaking, installations using it can reduce their RAM consumption at least a 70%. No action is needed to benefit from this optimization other than upgrading your installation to v2.</description></item><item><title>Improving The Developer Experience of Your APIs</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/improving-developer-experience-moesif-krakend/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/improving-developer-experience-moesif-krakend/</guid><description>Contributor note This is a guest post by Matt Tanner, Head of Developer Relations at Moesif, our advanced API Analytics, Governance, and Monetization partners. Matt utilizes his extensive experience to help developers and product managers optimize the Moesif platform. As a modern organization, you’re likely building many APIs. Most are exposed internally and externally, allowing developers of varying backgrounds to leverage them. Building APIs developers love to use is the key to adoption, success, and growth.</description></item><item><title>Automating License Validity Checks with KrakenD</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/automating-license-check/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 13:25:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/automating-license-check/</guid><description>KrakenD&amp;rsquo;s Enterprise Edition offers a feature for automated license validity checks. While we at KrakenD always take a proactive role in renewals and interim replacements, we understand the importance of automated systems in avoiding oversights, especially in critical components like your API gateway.
Why Monitor License Validity? Monitoring license validity is a crucial step in maintaining operational stability, particularly as your business scales. An expired license could lead to unexpected disruptions in your API gateway, a key component in your infrastructure.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD Enterprise v2.6 released with OpenTelemetry, FIPS-140, gRPC server and more</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-ee-2.6-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-ee-2.6-release-notes/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re rolling out KrakenD Enterprise v2.6, and it&amp;rsquo;s packed with new features and improvements that make managing your APIs smoother and more efficient. This version builds on everything you know and love about KrakenD Community 2.6, adding even more to the mix. Let&amp;rsquo;s break down what&amp;rsquo;s new without the fluff.
Observability and monitoring OpenTelemetry integration: We&amp;rsquo;ve integrated OpenTelemetry to give you a better way to keep an eye on your APIs through tracing and metrics.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD CE v2.6 released with OpenTelemetry</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.6-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 14:25:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.6-release-notes/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re thrilled to share the latest KrakenD Community Edition v2.6 updates, focusing on enhancing observability, plugin development, and JWT validation. This release introduces significant improvements, new features, and an emphasis on OpenTelemetry integration.
Developers of plugins will find a new command to test plugins before you deploy them. While developing them, there is also access to more data, like the KrakenD context or the internal request, which allows for more imaginative plugins.</description></item><item><title>From OpenCensus to OpenTelemetry</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/from-opencensus-to-opentelemetry/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 12:25:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/from-opencensus-to-opentelemetry/</guid><description>In deployments of complex, distributed, and cloud-native environments, understanding the intricacies of application behavior and performance is crucial, and this is why KrakenD integrated advanced telemetry six years ago through OpenCensus and native metrics.
With the release of KrakenD v2.6, we have created an integration for OpenTelemetry and marks a significant evolution in its observability capabilities, providing users with enhanced insights and diagnostics tools.
What are the benefits of the OTEL integration OpenTelemetry represents a pivotal shift in how telemetry data is collected and managed.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD 2023: Milestones and New Horizons</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/2023-recap/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/2023-recap/</guid><description>As the year 2023 draws to a close, we at KrakenD are taking a moment to reflect on the incredible journey we&amp;rsquo;ve embarked upon together. It&amp;rsquo;s been a year marked by achievements, growth, and a relentless pursuit of excellence. We&amp;rsquo;re deeply grateful to our customers and the vibrant community that has supported us every step of the way. Your enthusiasm and trust have been the driving forces behind our success.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD Enterprise v2.5 released with API Monetization</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-ee-2.5-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-ee-2.5-release-notes/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re excited to announce the latest release v2.5 of KrakenD Enterprise, packed with powerful features and enhancements to make your API gateway experience even more seamless and robust. Needless to say, the KrakenD Enterprise v2.5 contains everything in the KrakenD Community 2.5 and a lot more. Let&amp;rsquo;s dive into the key changes in this release:
API Monetization and Governance Ooh la la! Our first release of KrakenD with API Monetization, in partnership with Moesif, which allows you to charge for your APIs based on usage, check the analytics, and set governance rules that KrakenD keeps in-sync in real time.</description></item><item><title>How KrakenD API Gateway uses JSON Schema</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/json-schema-use-case/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/json-schema-use-case/</guid><description>Adopting best practices in the dynamic realm of API development is critical to ensuring data integrity, security, and seamless interactions.
In our experience, JSON Schema (project website) emerged as a fundamental tool in this journey. Since we started using it, the developer experience has dramatically improved for KrakenD core developers and KrakenD users.
KrakenD uses JSON Schema mainly for five very distinct use cases (though there are more):
Validating incoming requests on runtime Ensure complete responses before returning them to users Validate configuration files in deployment and build processes.</description></item><item><title>API Response Manipulation: Enhanced Control and Flexibility</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/response-manipulation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 10:25:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/response-manipulation/</guid><description>&amp;nbsp; Table of contents Ready-to-Use Options for Response Manipulation 1. Comprehensive Manipulations: Aggregation, Filtering, Grouping, Mapping 2. Enhancing Response Manipulations with Martian 3. Enhanced Manipulation with Regular Expressions 4. Advanced Content Manipulation with a Query Language 5. Advanced Response Manipulation with Templates: Power and Versatility Extensible Options for Tailored Response Manipulation 6. Lua Scripting 7. Request / Response Custom Plugin Modifiers Conclusion: KrakenD - Power, Flexibility, and Simplicity in API Management KrakenD is a versatile tool for API management that shines in handling the complex aspects of API-based systems, and is particularly noted for its backend response manipulation.</description></item><item><title>Keep-Alive Connections And Its Critical Role While Optimizing API Performance</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/keep-alive-optimizing-performance/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 20:25:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/keep-alive-optimizing-performance/</guid><description>An important yet often overlooked aspect while optimizing API performance is the management of HTTP keep-alive connections. KrakenD, an advanced API Gateway, offers an array of configuration parameters that significantly influence these connections. This post delves into these parameters, elucidating how they affect API performance.
Understanding Keep-Alive in HTTP HTTP keep-alive is a protocol mechanism that maintains an open connection between the client and the server. It allows multiple requests and responses over a single connection, reducing the overhead of establishing new connections, thus enhancing API performance.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD CE v2.5 released: multiple POSTs opened</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.5-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.5-release-notes/</guid><description>Hey KrakenD enthusiasts,
We&amp;rsquo;ve got some exciting news for you – KrakenD v2.5 is here, packed with features that take simplicity to a whole new level while tackling complex challenges head-on. Let&amp;rsquo;s dive right into the key updates that make this release worth upgrading:
Multiple POSTs When we created the aggregation feature seven years ago, we considered it too dangerous for our users to open the door to allow aggregation and sequential calls to write data to multiple targets from a single API call.</description></item><item><title>Enhancing KrakenD operations with complementing technologies</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/complementary-technologies/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 10:01:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/complementary-technologies/</guid><description>&amp;nbsp; Table of contents Local Development &amp;amp; Debugging Deployment &amp;amp; Orchestration Continuous Integration/Continuous Deployment (CI/CD) Load Balancing &amp;amp; Scalability Service Mesh &amp;amp; Internal Traffic Management Security / Auth Streaming, Queuing &amp;amp; Event-Driven Communication Monitoring, Visualization &amp;amp; Performance Optimization Conclusion Exploring platform architecture often highlights the potential of technology collaborations. KrakenD stands out by aligning effortlessly with a variety of specialized solutions and technical stacks, thanks to its unopinionated design approach.</description></item><item><title>Upgrade to mitigate the Rapid Reset Attack vulnerability</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.4.6-ce-2.4.2-ee-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.4.6-ce-2.4.2-ee-release-notes/</guid><description>A new patch version KrakenD Enterprise 2.4.2, and another for KrakenD Community 2.4.6 is available on the download page and the Docker registry, addressing a critical security issue related to Distributed Denial of Service (DDoS) vulnerabilities in HTTP/2 server implementations
More specifically this upgrade addresses CVE-2023-44487 and CVE-2023-39325&amp;quot;, known as the &amp;ldquo;Rapid Reset Attack.&amp;rdquo;
These vulnerabilities have been rated with a CVSSv3 Score of 7.5 and are classified as having an important security impact.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD Training: The Definitive Certification Program for API Gateway Mastery</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-api-gateway-training-certification/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2023 13:25:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-api-gateway-training-certification/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re thrilled to unveil KrakenD Training, a certification program that stands out in its depth and breadth. Crafted by the very engineers who developed KrakenD, this program is designed for tech professionals who are serious about mastering the full spectrum of features offered by KrakenD&amp;rsquo;s API Gateway.
Why Choose KrakenD Training? In an industry where specialized knowledge is your strongest asset, KrakenD Training offers:
Technical Depth: The course covers KrakenD&amp;rsquo;s extensive feature set, ensuring you become proficient in a wide range of use cases.</description></item><item><title>Unlocking the Power of OpenAPI with KrakenD Enterprise</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/openapi-krakend-enterprise/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2023 13:25:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/openapi-krakend-enterprise/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;re in the API game, you&amp;rsquo;ve likely heard of the OpenAPI Specification (OAS). But have you ever wondered how to leverage it to its fullest potential? In this blog post, we&amp;rsquo;ll dive deep into what OpenAPI is, its key use cases, and how KrakenD Enterprise customers can harness its capabilities to streamline their API management.
What is OpenAPI? OpenAPI is a specification for building APIs. It serves as a blueprint that describes how your API works and what it can do.</description></item><item><title>Mastering API Rate Limiting with KrakenD: A Comprehensive Guide</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/api-rate-limit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2023 13:25:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/api-rate-limit/</guid><description>When it comes to managing APIs effectively with KrakenD, understanding the intricacies of rate limiting is essential. This guide provides a deep dive into rate limiting within KrakenD, covering its importance, types, best practices, and future trends.
Understanding Rate Limiting in KrakenD: Types and Roles Rate limiting serves multiple functions, from resource allocation and security to ensuring API availability. KrakenD offers a variety of rate limiting options to suit different needs:</description></item><item><title>Automating the Software Bill of Materials (SBOM)</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/generating-a-sbom/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 11:25:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/generating-a-sbom/</guid><description>We can define a Software Bill of Materials (SBOM) as a comprehensive inventory of open-source and third-party components within a codebase.
It includes component licenses, versions, and patch status to assess security and license risks. This concept draws inspiration from manufacturing, where product inventory lists are vital. Like an automotive Bill of Materials, an SBOM helps identify and address issues in software components efficiently.
Organizations need SBOMs due to security breaches, prompting cybersecurity guidelines.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD Enterprise 2.4.1 (bugfixing) released</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-ee-2.4.1-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-ee-2.4.1-release-notes/</guid><description>The new KrakenD Enterprise version 2.4.1 is already available for install or upgrade. This patch version fixes primarly WebSocket connectivity.
🚀 Summary of changes for EEv2.4 This release fixes the buffer size of WebSocket messages.
WebSocket messages larger than 4KB were split despite overriding this behavior with max_message_size Corrected the $schema URL when using the --lint flag to point to the correct version Corrected a continuos restart of the :watch Docker container when using the new Advanced Flexible Configuration for the first time Upgrading to the latest version is always advised.</description></item><item><title>Securing Sensitive Data with KrakenD API Data Masking</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/api-data-masking/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 13:25:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/api-data-masking/</guid><description>Securing sensitive data is a non-negotiable requirement for organizations. API data masking is a robust security measure that can help you achieve this. This article dives into the mechanics of API data masking and how KrakenD&amp;rsquo;s features like regex content replacer and response body generator can make this process more efficient and compliant.
Understanding API Data Masking API data masking is a technique that replaces original data with random or pseudonymous data.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD Enterprise v2.4: New Power and Efficiency</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-ee-2.4-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-ee-2.4-release-notes/</guid><description>We are thrilled to announce the upcoming release of KrakenD API Gateway v2.4 (download, a significant step forward in enhancing your API management experience. Packed with an array of powerful features and improvements, this release is set to improve the way you manage and optimize your APIs.
As the API landscape evolves, KrakenD remains dedicated to providing cutting-edge tools to optimize and manage your APIs. The v2.4 release showcases our commitment to innovation, flexibility, and security, ensuring that you have the best possible resources at your disposal.</description></item><item><title>Securing Your Microservices and APIs: The KrakenD Way</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/securing-your-microservices/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 13:25:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/securing-your-microservices/</guid><description>In today&amp;rsquo;s world, where everything is going digital, we can&amp;rsquo;t overemphasize the importance of keeping your APIs and microservices safe. Cyber threats are an everyday reality, and they don&amp;rsquo;t care how big or complex your infrastructure is. They just want a way in. This is where KrakenD, a leading API gateway company, steps in. We&amp;rsquo;ve got your back with our robust solution, built around a zero-trust policy, OWASP guidelines, and a bunch of other cool stuff to bolster your API security.</description></item><item><title>The Importance of an API Gateway in Modern Services Architecture</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/importance-of-api-gateway-modern-services-architecture/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 13:25:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/importance-of-api-gateway-modern-services-architecture/</guid><description>How KrakenD Steers the Fleet As we traverse the evolving landscape of modern services architecture, the significance of an API Gateway cannot be overstated. At KrakenD, we are not just participating in this evolution but leading it. We have channeled our expertise into developing an API Gateway solution that is efficient, scalable, and perfectly tuned to meet the specific needs of the digital age.
What is an API Gateway? Think of an API Gateway as the touchpoint that connects your clients to your backend services.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD CE 2.4.2 and EE 2.3.3 security fixes</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.4.2-ce-2.3.3-ee-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.4.2-ce-2.3.3-ee-release-notes/</guid><description>A new patch version KrakenD Enterprise 2.3.3, and another for KrakenD Community 2.4.2 is available on the download page and the Docker registry. Upgrading from any 2.x is backward compatible.
The following security fixes do not seem to have any impact on KrakenD after all the tests performed, but a patch is offered as a cautionary measure.
🚀 Summary of changes for CEv2.4 We have updated our internal libraries to rectify security issues identified in scans.</description></item><item><title>REST vs gRPC vs GraphQL in KrakenD: A Comprehensive Comparison</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/rest-grpc-graphql-krakend-comparison/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 13:25:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/rest-grpc-graphql-krakend-comparison/</guid><description>Understanding the landscape of APIs and making the right choice can seem daunting, especially with a myriad of available technologies. This is where KrakenD, your trusted partner in API management, steps in. We offer an in-depth comparison of three leading technologies: REST, gRPC, and GraphQL, examining their strengths, drawbacks, and how they integrate with KrakenD.
REST: The Reliable Partner Enhanced by KrakenD REST (Representational State Transfer) is a time-tested, reliable technology in the API world.</description></item><item><title>Canary releases with KrakenD: Safely roll out API changes</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/canary-releases/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/canary-releases/</guid><description>Canary release is a powerful technique that helps organizations deploy changes to their APIs in a controlled and gradual manner. Instead of publishing changes to receive the impact of all traffic when going live, you expose the changes to a small subset of the traffic. The Canary Release allows for thorough monitoring and validation, reducing the risk of potential issues affecting the entire system.
This blog post will explore three ways of implementing Canary Releases on KrakenD, ensuring smoother deployments and enhanced reliability.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD 2.4.1 (patch version) released</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.4.1-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.4.1-release-notes/</guid><description>A new patch version KrakenD 2.4.1 is available on the download page and the Docker registry. Upgrading from any 2.x is backward compatible.
🚀 Summary of changes for CEv2.4 Fix on the new rate limit component
The rate limit did not load because its namespace was internally rewritten using an ancient namespace (KrakenD v1) Upgrading to the latest version is always advised. Compare versions Upgrade to v2.4.1</description></item><item><title>KrakenD CE v2.4 released!</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.4-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.4-release-notes/</guid><description>The KrakenD team is pleased to announce the release of KrakenD Community Edition v2.4, which improves configuration granularity, and a more user-friendly rate limit.
You can get v2.4 packaged for several options from the download page.
🚀 Summary of changes for CEv2.4 The v2.4 improves the rate limit usage experience to support non-second time intervals, and offers more granularity option to improve security.
A rewritten rate limit introduces the every component, allowing to set limits per second, minute, or hour.</description></item><item><title>Modernizing your legacy SOAP services with KrakenD</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/modernizing-soap-services/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/modernizing-soap-services/</guid><description>We are thrilled to introduce one of our latest features: SOAP integration. This powerful integration is designed to help businesses modernize their legacy SOAP systems without the need for extensive modifications.
Understanding SOAP and Its Limitations SOAP (Simple Object Access Protocol) is a protocol specification for exchanging structured information in web services using XML. It operates over HTTP for simplicity and compatibility, but also supports other protocols such as SMTP. SOAP&amp;rsquo;s primary application is in large-scale enterprise environments with high security and transactional requirements.</description></item><item><title>Step-by-step Migration Guide: From AWS API Gateway to KrakenD API Gateway</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/migrate-aws-api-gateway-to-krakend/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 13:25:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/migrate-aws-api-gateway-to-krakend/</guid><description>Introduction As you consider migrating from AWS API Gateway to KrakenD API Gateway, you&amp;rsquo;re likely driven by a number of compelling benefits such as a better pricing model, reduced vendor lock-in, operational simplicity, enhanced content manipulation and transformation capabilities, increased connectivity protocols, and extensibility trough Custom golang Plugins or Lua scripts. This guide will walk you through the primary steps and considerations in this migration process.
Pre-Migration Before starting the migration process, it&amp;rsquo;s essential to make sure to map your existing API Gateway resources to equivalent KrakenD concepts, which include endpoints, routers, and backends.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD Enterprise 2.3.2 (bugfixing) released</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-ee-2.3.2-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-ee-2.3.2-release-notes/</guid><description>The new KrakenD Enterprise version 2.3.2 is already available for install or upgrade. This patch version fixes a few corner cases of several components that could not work properly in edge scenarios.
🚀 Summary of changes for EEv2.3 Small fixes on Redis rate limiter, gRPC, API keys, and Lua
Lua: Corrected bug not preventing lists to grow, and added a special type for nil treatment. API Keys: When a user key is valid, but it does not have permissions to use the resource now a 403 is returned instead of the 401 gRPC: Fix types of recursive objects Better logging on plugins Redis rate-limit: Fix a corner-case panic during startup Upgrading to the latest version is always advised.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD Enterprise 2.3.1 (bugfixing) released</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-ee-2.3.1-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-ee-2.3.1-release-notes/</guid><description>The new KrakenD Enterprise version 2.3.1 is already available for install or upgrade. This patch version fixes a few corner cases of several components that could not work properly in edge scenarios. It also adds two small new Lua functions for working with tables and lists.
🚀 Summary of changes for EEv2.3 Fixes on Redis rate limiter, Alpine security upgrade, body generator, gRPC, and added new helpers in Lua
Add list and table helpers to Lua scripts Automatically set content-type application/json for GraphQL backends, no longer needing the client to pass it + fixes in formatting Fix escaped chars during XML rendering Avoid startup panic when using proxy rate limit with capacity 0 Bodygenerator: Push Content-Length header with the calculation of a generated body.</description></item><item><title>Introducing versioning in JSON schema validation</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/changes-in-json-schema/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/changes-in-json-schema/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re excited to announce some significant changes to the JSON schema validation in KrakenD. These updates are aimed at improving versioning and organization, providing clearer support for different KrakenD versions, and enabling broader usage of JSON schemas beyond just configuration files. Let&amp;rsquo;s delve into the details of these changes.
From a unique schema to one schema per version Previously to writing this post, we had a single schema validation URL (https://www.</description></item><item><title>Understanding API Calls: The KrakenD Approach</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/api-calls/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 13:25:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/api-calls/</guid><description>KrakenD, a market leader in high-performance API Gateway solutions, enables seamless and efficient API interactions within today&amp;rsquo;s complex digital landscape. This comprehensive guide delves into the intricate details of API calls and their pivotal role within the microservices architecture, specifically in a KrakenD environment.
Understanding API Calls: The Essence of Software Interactions APIs, or Application Programming Interfaces, form the core of sophisticated software interactions, providing the pathways for communication between different software modules.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD 2.3.3 (patch version) released</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.3.3-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.3.3-release-notes/</guid><description>A new patch version KrakenD 2.3.3 is available on the download page and the Docker registry. Upgrading from any 2.x is backward compatible.
This release includes a security fix to mitigate SSL3 CVE-2023-1255 (Base Score: 5.9 MEDIUM) and new Lua helpers fo facilitate developments of custom business logic. The new Lua helpers are:
luaTable.new(), which returns a new table. t:keys(), which returns the sorted key names of a table t. luaList.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD Enterprise v2.3: Easing Your API Journey</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-ee-2.3-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-ee-2.3-release-notes/</guid><description>KrakenD Enterprise is excited to announce the release of its API gateway software v2.3, available for download. This upgrade delivers an improved experience for users looking to simplify their operations.
With KrakenD v2.3, users will experience greater simplicity, eliminating the need for several plugins and adding automated processes to import OpenAPI and gRPC contracts.
This upgrade has been designed to address the joint pain points customers experience when managing their APIs.</description></item><item><title>Optimize you API Gateway Management with Flexible Configuration</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/unleash-power-flexible-configuration/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/unleash-power-flexible-configuration/</guid><description>Flexible Configuration is a template-based configuration system for KrakenD API Gateway that allows you to manage configurations efficiently and cater to multiple environments. In this blog post, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore the pain-points it addresses and the benefits it brings to customers.
Challenges solved by Flexible Configuration Organizing and managing configurations can be challenging, especially when:
Configurations are extensive and need to be split into multiple files You need to inject environment-specific variables Reusable code blocks and placeholders are necessary to avoid repetition Multiple developers are working on the API gateway KrakenD is managed using multiple repositories Tracking changes, avoiding conflicts, and reviewing code is crucial Flexible Configuration is designed to tackle these pain-points effectively.</description></item><item><title>Benefits of a Stateless API Gateway</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/benefits-of-stateless-api-gateway/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/benefits-of-stateless-api-gateway/</guid><description>API Gateways play a crucial role in modern software architecture, enabling developers to manage and route traffic between client applications and backend services. KrakenD stands out due to its stateless design, which provides several significant advantages over other solutions.
What is a Stateless API Gateway? A stateless API Gateway is an APII Gateway that doesn&amp;rsquo;t depend on a centralized database for storing configurations or maintaining a shared &amp;ldquo;state.&amp;rdquo; Instead, each instance of the API Gateway possesses its own configuration file, read when the service initiates.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD 2.3.2 (patch version) released</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.3.2-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.3.2-release-notes/</guid><description>A new patch version KrakenD 2.3.2 is available on the download page and the Docker registry. Upgrading from any 2.x is backward compatible.
🚀 Summary of changes for CEv2.3 Fixed plugin builder and corrected edge cases in JWT validation.
Custom plugins: Alpine image builder fixed for ARM64 JWT: Panic when receiving an invalid number of claims JWT: Remove misleading error log when no global cache is defined JWT: index out of range Upgrade to Go version 1.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD 2.3.1 (patch version) released</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.3.1-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.3.1-release-notes/</guid><description>A new patch version KrakenD 2.3.1 is available to download page. Upgrading from any 2.x is backwards compatible.
🚀 Summary of changes for CEv2.3 The new TLS Client functionality was not included in the release.
The deny attribute did not work on the third nesting level and above. The new client_tls attribute was not yet included. Upgrading to the latest version is always advised. Compare versions Upgrade to v2.3.1</description></item><item><title>KrakenD CE v2.3 released!</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.3-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.3-release-notes/</guid><description>The KrakenD team is pleased to announce the release of KrakenD Community Edition v2.3, which improves connectivity with backends, caching, and adds the possibility to play with KrakenD using the web Designer directly.
You can get v2.3 packaged for several options from the download page.
🚀 Summary of changes for CEv2.3 The v2.3 adds more connectivity options with backends and caching and adds the possibility to load changes into a local KrakenD using the Designer (UI) directly.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD Enterprise 2.2.1 (bugfixing) released</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-ee-2.2.1-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-ee-2.2.1-release-notes/</guid><description>The new KrakenD Enterprise version 2.2.1 is already available for install or upgrade. This patch version does not bring significant new functionality (except for AMQP) but includes a few fixes.
🚀 Summary of changes for EEv2.2 Enables backoff strategies for AMQP producers and consumers, and fixes OpenAPI generation issues.
AMQP consumers and producers offer now retries with several backoff strategies. Request modifier plugin loader is now hardened and is more strict to prevent human error.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD Enterprise 2.2 released</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-ee-2.2-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-ee-2.2-release-notes/</guid><description>The new KrakenD Enterprise version 2.2 is now available, and it&amp;rsquo;s supercharged: Introduces dynamic routing based on headers and query strings, adds a security policies engine, upgrades to OpenAPI 3, improves SOAP integration, default gzip compression and a lot more&amp;hellip;
Below there is a summary of changes and an introduction to some of these new features.
Security Policies: Enforce any check, anywhere From RBAC and ABAC, to lifecycle management, restriction of content by country, validation custom cryptography or other strategies, &amp;hellip; The new policies engine allows you to do any custom evaluations you need, during runtime and with access to query strings, URLs, parameters, cookies, tokens, time functions, geolocation, cryptography, and a long etcetera.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD 2.2.1 (patch version) released</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.2.1-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.2.1-release-notes/</guid><description>A new patch version KrakenD 2.2.1 is available to download page. Upgrading from any 2.x does not require changes in the configuration.
🚀 Summary of changes for CEv2.2 Fixes a memory leak on Shadow Proxies.
Fixed memory leak on Shadow Proxies when the response wasn&amp;rsquo;t a 200 Fixed audit command that would still warn on some fixed issues Upgraded Go to version 1.20.1 Upgrading to the latest version is always advised.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD 2.2 Release Notes: Latest Features and Enhancements</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.2-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.2-release-notes/</guid><description>The KrakenD team is pleased to announce the release of KrakenD Community Edition v2.2. It introduces a new security audit command (krakend audit) that parses and analyzes your configurations and outputs security recommendations. We have designed it to run as a standalone command or integrated it into your existing CI/CD pipeline to avoid dangerous configurations, such as unwillingly disabling the TLS, setting excessive timeouts, unprotected endpoints, or similar scenarios.
You can get v2.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD Enterprise 2.1.2 (security fix) released</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-ee-2.1.2-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-ee-2.1.2-release-notes/</guid><description>The new KrakenD Enterprise version 2.1.2 is already available for install or upgrade. This patch version does not bring significant new functionality but updates dependencies that have security vulnerabilities and adds a few fixes:
🚀 Summary of changes for EEv2.1 The patch v2.1.2 updates dependencies that have security vulnerabilities.
Add the content-type header when returning errors Upgrade from Go 1.19.3 to Go 1.19.5, which includes security fixes to the net/http, crypto/x509, and os packages, among others.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD 2.1.4 (security fix) released</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.1.4-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.1.4-release-notes/</guid><description>The new KrakenD version 2.1.4 is now available. This patch version does not bring significant new functionality but updates dependencies that have security vulnerabilities and adds a few fixes:
🚀 Summary of changes for CEv2.1 Corrects a bug when caching Gzipped content and adds the Content-Type header when returning errors.
Add the Content-Type header when returning errors Upgrade from Go 1.19.3 to Go 1.19.5, which includes security fixes to the net/http, crypto/x509, and os packages, among others.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD 2022 Recap: A Look Back at Our Major Milestones</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/2022-recap/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/2022-recap/</guid><description>We can&amp;rsquo;t believe it&amp;rsquo;s been six years since the first commit to KrakenD. It&amp;rsquo;s incredible how fast time passes when you have a purpose, and we&amp;rsquo;ve had a blast working on this project and seeing it grow. We are so grateful to everyone who has been with us on this journey.
At KrakenD, we are passionate about building an open-source API Gateway that pursues performance, scalability, and simplicity. This past year marked our first full year as an independent company.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD 2.1.1 EE (patch version) released</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-ee-2.1.1-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-ee-2.1.1-release-notes/</guid><description>The new KrakenD Enterprise version 2.1.1 is already available for install or upgrade. This patch version does not bring new API Gateway functionality but adds support for ARM64 and other improvements.
🚀 Summary of changes for EEv2.1 The patch v2.1.1 fixes logging on the wildcard and a race condition on OpenAPI generation.
Fix OpenAPI race condition Fix wildcard plugin logger messages Upgrading to the latest version is always advised.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD 2.1.3 (patch version) released</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.1.3-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.1.3-release-notes/</guid><description>The new KrakenD version 2.1.3 is now available. This patch version does not bring new API Gateway functionality but adds support for ARM64 and other improvements.
🚀 Summary of changes for CEv2.1 ARM64 support, and obfuscate the KrakenD version header.
Now officially supporting ARM64 architectures, releasing new Docker containers and packages. Performance improvement on Lambda usage A new flag, hide_version_header, placed in the router settings, allows obfuscating the X-Krakend-Version header. JSON Schema: Return a 400 status code when the body is empty or a malformed JSON (thanks to @efcasado) Reject requests with special chars in the params Upgrading to the latest version is always advised.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD Enterprise 2.1 released</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-ee-2.1-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-ee-2.1-release-notes/</guid><description>The KrakenD team is pleased to announce the release of KrakenD Enterprise 2.1, already available for install or upgrade.
Apologies because we have added so much that the summary is not going to be short this time :)
🚀 Summary of changes for EEv2.1 KrakenD Enterprise v2.1 brings a lot of new functionality, including advanced manipulation with a JSON Query language, a Revoke Server to manage tokens in clusters, new Kibana and Grafana dashboards, faster encoding, a rewritten and richer NewRelic exporter, Websockets balancing, everything on Community 2.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD becomes a CNA (CVE Numbering Authority)</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-becomes-a-cna/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-becomes-a-cna/</guid><description>The Spanish National Cybersecurity Institute (INCIBE) announces today the addition of KrakenD as a CNA (CVE Numbering Authority). KrakenD assumes as its own, from this date, the best practices of this program.
KrakenD is now authorized by the CVE Program to assign CVE identifiers within its scope and its corresponding publication in the CNA section. Information technology and cybersecurity professionals use CVE Records to ensure they are discussing the same issue, and to coordinate their efforts to prioritize and address the vulnerabilities.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD 2.1.2 (patch version) released</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.1.2-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.1.2-release-notes/</guid><description>A new patch version KrakenD 2.1.2 is available to download page. This release fixes a bug while parsing placeholders in endpoint.
🚀 Summary of changes for CEv2.1 Corrects a bug with parameters sent to the backend
Some requests sent to backend didn&amp;rsquo;t have the parameters replaced from the client URL Upgrading to the latest version is always advised. Compare versions Upgrade to v2.1.2</description></item><item><title>KrakenD 2.1.1 (patch version) released</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.1.1-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.1.1-release-notes/</guid><description>A new patch version KrakenD 2.1.1 is available to download page. In addition to the patch, we have created a new plugin-builder Docker image for those who compile custom plugins.
🚀 Summary of changes for CEv2.1 Adds a Docker image to build plugins and fixes issues with the JOSE and Lua packages.
Bot Detector: Avoid aborting with an error Influx: Logs normalized for better consistency JOSE: Use a sempahore to orchestrate the concurrent warm up of the JWK caches Lambda: Upgrade the AWS SDK version used (by @boris154) The krakend check command did not accept configurations with zero number of endpoints.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD 2.1 released!</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.1-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.1-release-notes/</guid><description>The KrakenD team is pleased to announce the release of KrakenD 2.1. You can get it packaged from the download page.
KrakenD 2.1 brings a new ready-to-use Kibana dashboard, an updated Grafana Dashboard for InfluxDB v2 and more features and bugfixes described below:
🚀 Summary of changes for CEv2.1 KrakenD 2.1 brings a new ready-to-use Kibana dashboard, an updated Grafana Dashboard for InfluxDB v2 and more features and bugfixes
New repository Telemetry Dashboards, including Kibana, Grafana, Logstash, and Influx v2 Added a krakend version command that outputs the KrakenD, Go, and Glibc versions.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD partners with Child Rescue Coalition</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-child-rescue-coalition-partnership/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-child-rescue-coalition-partnership/</guid><description>Barcelona, September 19th 2022.- KrakenD announces today the partnership with Child Rescue Coalition. Child Rescue Coalition (CRC) is a nonprofit organization whose mission is to rescue children from sexual abuse by building technology for law enforcement to track, arrest and prosecute child predators. KrakenD has donated an unlimited commercial license (KrakenD Enterprise) to CRC to help them build and scale their APIs-oriented technological platform.
CRC has contributed to rescuing more than 3,200 children from sexual exploitation and abuse.</description></item><item><title>IBM proposes KrakenD to replace IBM Cloud API Gateway</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-alternative-ibm-api-cloud/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-alternative-ibm-api-cloud/</guid><description>The IBM Cloud API Gateway service provided traffic limiting, splitting, and authentication for Cloud Functions and Cloud Foundry users. Unfortunately, IBM&amp;rsquo;s API Gateway service was deprecated and shut down on August 31st, 2022. Existing endpoints will no longer route to their respective functions or apps.
A blog post by IBM Cloud published on June 8th provided some tips and recommendations for IBM Cloud API Gateway users. For those users who still require an API Gateway as part of their platform architecture, KrakenD has been suggested as an alternative.</description></item><item><title>Adressing CVE-2022-1561: Crafted backend urls</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/cve-2022-1561-crafted-backend-urls/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/cve-2022-1561-crafted-backend-urls/</guid><description>&lt;p>There is a new vulnerability in the &lt;a href="https://luraproject.org/">Lura Project&lt;/a> software (which is the KrakenD&amp;rsquo;s engine). We have immediately corrected the problem in the subsequent release after its report. Please upgrade to the latest version.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>KrakenD Enterprise 2.0 released!</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-ee-2.0-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-ee-2.0-release-notes/</guid><description>The KrakenD team is pleased to announce KrakenD Enterprise 2.0, already available for install or upgrade today.
KrakenD 2.0 is the awaited new major version of KrakenD bringing a lot of improvements to the API Gateway, including all the features and improvements of open source releases between v1.4 and v2.0.4.
🚀 Summary of changes for EEv2.0 KrakenD Enterprise 2.0 is a major rework and needs migration. API Analytics, IP Filtering, GraphQL, OpenAPI importers and exporters, integration tests, specific request/modifier plugins, Async Agents, backend response logging (dumper) and improves the existing WebSockets, API Keys, configuration syntax, New Relic reporting, logging, and router to put a few examples.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD Now Available in the Azure Marketplace</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-partners-with-microsoft/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-partners-with-microsoft/</guid><description>BARCELONA, Spain — April 7, 2022
KrakenD today announced the availability of KrakenD API Gateway in the Microsoft Azure Marketplace, an online store providing applications and services for use on Microsoft Azure. KrakenD customers can now take advantage of the scalability, high availability, and security of Azure, with streamlined deployment and management.
The KrakenD API Gateway serves as a unified interface for managing incoming API requests and connecting to the correct destination, while supporting functionalities across security, authorization, traffic management, observability, and load balancing, among other services.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD 2.0 released!</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.0-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-2.0-release-notes/</guid><description>The KrakenD team is pleased to announce the major release KrakenD 2.0. You can get it packaged from the download page.
🚀 Summary of changes for CEv2.0 KrakenD 2.0 is the new major version of KrakenD bringing a lot of improvements to the API Gateway. GraphQL, specific request/modifier plugins, async agents, easier configuration, better logging, and a more flexible router to put a few examples.
REST to GraphQL conversion, or direct consumption of GraphQL through the gateway Backend response logging New plugin types (request/response) Plenty of new configurable router flags The krakend check adds verbosity level A new command krakend check-plugin for quicker development of custom plugins Shortened configuration namespaces.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD unnaffected by Log4j</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/log4j-vulnerability/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/log4j-vulnerability/</guid><description>The year 2021 ended with terrible news for Java developers who saw how the Log4J vulnerabilities exposed their systems.
KrakenD is a Go application and not a Java application. Therefore, it is not affected by this vulnerability in any way. As a result, we didn&amp;rsquo;t want to add more noise to the chain of emails you could have probably received.
Nevertheless, during the past month, we had questions from customers who have Java systems behind KrakenD that could be vulnerable and other users that weren&amp;rsquo;t sure if KrakenD was impacted or not.</description></item><item><title>Traffic mirroring: test APIs without tests</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-shadow-testing/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-shadow-testing/</guid><description>Integration and load testing are in the list of best practices in our sector, but synthesizing good inputs for such tests and analyzing the results are usually two hard things to achieve. This post will show you how we suggest our customers set up a shadow testing system with minimal impact on the production environment and proper harness.
Quick overview As pointed out at https://cloud.google.com/architecture/application-deployment-and-testing-strategies
Testing new backend features by using the production load.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD Now Available on Auth0 Marketplace</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-auth0-announcement/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-auth0-announcement/</guid><description>Barcelona – 15th June 2020 – KrakenD today announced the availability of its API Gateway on Auth0 Marketplace, a catalog of trusted technology integrations to extend the functionality of Auth0’s identity management platform. KrakenD offers an ultra-performant API Gateway that allows companies to effortlessly adopt a microservices architecture through a powerful engine that can transform, aggregate, and remove data from their own or third-party services.
The KrakenD API Gateway serves as a unified interface for managing incoming API requests and connecting to the correct destination, while supporting functionalities across security, authorization, traffic management, observability, and load balancing, among others.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD 1.4.0 released</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-1.4-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-1.4-release-notes/</guid><description>The KrakenD team is pleased to announce the release of KrakenD 1.4.0. You can get it packaged from the download page.
🚀 Summary of changes for CEv1.4 KrakenD 1.4 is the last version of the 1.x family and primarily replaces the KrakenD Framework with the Lura Project and includes minor bug fixing and an extended flexible configuration. The next release with the new functionality will be 2.0.
All dependencies for the framework moved to Lura The json-collection output encoding allows returning collections directly Added Sprig functions to Flexible Configuration Allow the propagation of nested claims using dot notation (JWT) Add the del method to Lua Upgrading to the latest version is always advised.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD Enterprise 1.3.0 released</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-ee-1.3-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-ee-1.3-release-notes/</guid><description>We are glad to announce that KrakenD Enterprise 1.3.0 is out. The new release comes with the following new features.
🚀 Summary of changes for EEv1.3 KrakenD Enterprise 1.3 includes everything in the Community v1.3 and adds generator commands for OpenAPI, Postman, and rendering PNG files with the configuration. It also adds support for wildcard routes.
New generate postman command New generate openapi command New generate config2dot command Support for wildcard routes Multiple identity providers Integration of secret providers Upgrading to the latest version is always advised.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD framework becomes a Linux Foundation project</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-framework-joins-the-linux-foundation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-framework-joins-the-linux-foundation/</guid><description>Today, together with the Linux Foundation, we are announcing that the KrakenD framework, our core engine, has been donated to the Linux Foundation and is now the &amp;ldquo;Lura Project.&amp;rdquo;
The Lura Project&amp;rsquo;s mission is to offer an extendable, simple, and stateless high-performance API Gateway framework designed for cloud-native and on-prem setups. Rather than solving a specific use case, Lura provides a library of components, a framework for assembling them into custom API gateway systems like a Lego set.</description></item><item><title>Albert Garcia to expand KrakenD business.</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/albert-garcia-expand-krakend-business/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/albert-garcia-expand-krakend-business/</guid><description>Today, we are announcing that Albert Garcia recently joined KrakenD as Director of Business Development and member of the Board.
In his role, he will identify and develop new business opportunities to help expand even more the presence of KrakenD. Garcia will spearhead new markets and emerging trends, sales, and client relationship management, to name a few.
Having worked previously with him for more than 15 years, we know that Garcia is the right person at the right time for KrakenD.</description></item><item><title>Building a Telemetry Service</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/building-a-telemetry-service/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 09:40:25 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/building-a-telemetry-service/</guid><description>​ We have run our telemetry system live for the past three years now. In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll share code and outline some of the things you&amp;rsquo;ll need to keep in mind if you want to build an anonymous usage reporting system for an open-source project as we did (at a ridiculous cost).
We will show you how to use our reporting client and the details of our actual reporting servers in case you are thinking in implementing a cost-efficient solution with high scalability.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD 1.3.0 released</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-1.3-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-1.3-release-notes/</guid><description>The KrakenD team is pleased to announce the release of KrakenD 1.3.0. You can get it packaged from the download page.
🚀 Summary of changes for CEv1.3 KrakenD 1.3.0 makes focus on completing the RBAC system regarding JWT.
Scopes validation (thanks to @chrisdennig) Extract and forward claims as headers (thanks to @chrisdennig) Support for Oracle Identity Cloud Service by allowing key identifers other than kid such as x5t or kid_x5t (contribution from Oracle) Allow loading of local JWK files Integration with secret providers such as, Amazon KMS, Azure&amp;rsquo;s Key Vault, Google Cloud KMS, Hashicorp&amp;rsquo;s Vault, Encrypted or plain base64 file Expose router request host to Lua virtual machine (thanks to Marc Ruiz from Stayforlong) Add X-Forwarded-Host header (thanks to Marc Ruiz from Stayforlong) Allow the extraction of client IP from custom headers Add debugging information to CORS component The Etcd component is no longer loaded in KrakenD-CE (but the repository is available for custom integrations) The WASM-based emulator in KrakenDesigner has been removed.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD 1.2.0 released</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-1.2-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-1.2-release-notes/</guid><description>The KrakenD team is pleased to announce the release of KrakenD 1.2. You can get it packaged from the download page.
Some of the highlights include:
Added a /__health endpoint Removed the wording whitelist and blacklist from all our products (#BlackLivesMatter) Datadog integration Array manipulation available after merging multiple backends KRAKEND_-like environment vars to override configuration A lot of small features and bugfixes 🚀 Summary of changes for CEv1.2 KrakenD 1.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD Usage Stats - March 2020</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/usage-stats-march-2020/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/usage-stats-march-2020/</guid><description>KrakenD servers with telemetry enabled help us to understand the usage of KrakenD in production. Last month we witnessed 356K running instances, and we wanted to share some data with you. 👇
From mid-March, we have seen an exciting increase in the number of KrakenD instances seen per day: x12! The trend is just beautiful, including the cumulative.
According to our internal definition, an instance is every time a KrakenD is started.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD 1.1 with Kafka integration released</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-1.1-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-1.1-release-notes/</guid><description>The KrakenD team is pleased to announce the release of KrakenD 1.1. You can get it packaged from the download page.
Some of the highlights include:
Kafka integration Extended Docker image Added Telemetry for Azure Monitor More performance improvements 🚀 Summary of changes for CEv1.1 KrakenD 1.1.0 adds Kafka integration, an extended Docker image, telemetry for Azure Monitor and performance improvements.
Corrected a bug in the httpsecure module. Lambda context as base64 json-encoded context Lua request and response helpers Upgraded to Go 1.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD 1.0 announcement</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/announcing-krakend-1.0/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/announcing-krakend-1.0/</guid><description>In November 2016, we released KrakenD framework to the public. Today, after three years serving traffic around the world, and a lot of lessons learned on the way, KrakenD 1.0 is out 🎉🎉🎉
KrakenD 1.0 is our announcement to the world that our libraries are now fully established and with the solid commitment of keeping backward compatibility. In the last twelve months, we have seen 120,000+ clusters in the world and 1M+ docker pulls, but as we always did (since 0.</description></item><item><title>How to write a simple gRPC-gateway as a KrakenD plugin</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-grpc-gateway-plugin/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2019 18:26:10 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-grpc-gateway-plugin/</guid><description>The gRPC protocol is becoming trendy in the era of microservices. Its compactness and backward-compatibility make it very attractive. However, it requires custom code to work with it. In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll show you how to get all the benefits from the gRPC protocol and the gRPC-gateway without coding any business logic to use your gRPC services as regular backends. Moreover, avoiding the extra network hop!</description></item><item><title>Doing housekeeping on your configuration file</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/housekeeping-configuration-file/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/housekeeping-configuration-file/</guid><description>Starting your krakend.json configuration from scratch and writing every attribute in a blank editor might be a difficult and time consuming task, and that&amp;rsquo;s why we have the KrakenDesigner.
KrakenDesigner is an aid tool to generate KrakenD configurations for the uninitiated audience. It produces a verbose output of the configuration file and explicitly writes unneeded attributes to let you see that a specific configuration option exists. These attributes I am mentioning are not necessary because they contain default values and the server is not going to alter its behavior.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD 0.9 released</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-0.9-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-0.9-release-notes/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been only one month since we released KrakenD 0.8, and although we have been releasing new versions approximately every 3 months, we have very interesting features that can&amp;rsquo;t wait! KrakenD 0.9 comes with a series of very demanded features. Let&amp;rsquo;s get started!
Integration with AMQP The AMQP integration allows you to send and receive messages to and from a queue through the KrakenD API Gateway. This feature enables the gateway to become in both a subscriber and a consumer of messages for asynchronous processing and opens the doors to very different implementations we were seeing.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD 0.8 released</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-0.8-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-0.8-release-notes/</guid><description>KrakenD 0.8 is a significant release as it brings numerous code changes and functionality. The framework brings +100 commits, the gateway +50 commits and even more changes in the components. A lot of refactoring and component updates has taken place. The big picture is a move from a single binary application to become a package with several internal binaries.
See the details below.
KrakenD framework The KrakenD framework brings +100 commits compared to 0.</description></item><item><title>How we run KrakenD on Javascript with WebAssembly</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-wasm/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-wasm/</guid><description>KrakenD is an API Gateway written in Go that uses a single configuration file to define its whole behavior. As the configuration file might be complicated, the KrakenDesigner is a javascript-based user interface to edit this file, and we were missing the capability of reproducing directly on javascript the existing gateway pipes so that users could run manual tests over the editing configuration.
In this post, we are going to explain how we included KrakenD framework components in a .</description></item><item><title>KrakenD 0.7 released</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-0.7-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-0.7-release-notes/</guid><description>The most relevant features for the 0.7 release are increased metrics and tracing options, and functionality that has been requested by many, the sequential proxy merger. During this release, we also updated the KrakenD brand with a new logo, and we added more documentation.
On the metrics side, we can now send structured events using GELF to your Graylog Cluster. Opencensus middleware adds new functionality to push metrics to your Google StackDriver account.</description></item><item><title>Krakend 0.6.1 release notes</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-0.6.1-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 09:15:49 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-0.6.1-release-notes/</guid><description>The 0.6.1 release adds TLS and enables HTTP2 and HTTPS.
TL;DR This release brings HTTP2 and HTTPS to KrakenD. It also upgrades Go from 1.10 to 1.11 and fixes forwarded query string parameters to backends that are using arrays and repeated variables.
The KrakenDesigner (UI) is also updated to reflect these changes.
KrakenD framework The KrakenD framework has the following relevant changes:
NEW: Added support for HTTP2/HTTPS FIX: query string parameters works now with arrays and repeated variables (e.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD 0.6 autumn release</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-0.6-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 09:18:53 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-0.6-release-notes/</guid><description>As if we were an agrarian society, our releases keep revolving around the weather calendar seasons. Autumn is around the corner (northern hemisphere), so our release is ready for a cool autumn.
TL;DR This release adds two interesting components: the JOSE component responsible for the JWT signing and validation, and the Cross-origin resource sharing (CORS) component. There is also a Consul client available.
The Krakend Playground and the KrakenDesigner (UI) is also updated.</description></item><item><title>Reloading the config with Reflex and Docker</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/reloading-the-krakend-configuration/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 11:06:53 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/reloading-the-krakend-configuration/</guid><description>Read the new documentation This is an article from 2018. You might want to see the Hot reload documentation. A recurrent question when we go around is if KrakenD configuration can be hot-reloaded, this is changing endpoints, backends, or any other configuration of the gateway while it&amp;rsquo;s running. The short answer is: No, you can&amp;rsquo;t. You must restart the server. And although we might have something to alleviate this, let us explain first why we don&amp;rsquo;t support such a feature:</description></item><item><title>KrakenD 0.5 summer release</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-0.5-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 14:50:53 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-0.5-release-notes/</guid><description>KrakenD 0.5 is out and we want to share some of the cool stuff this release is bringing.
This release focuses heavily on metrics and its export options to different backend systems such as Zipkin, InfluxDB, Prometheus or Jaeger. It also adds the NoOp logger and exposes all the advanced settings of the http client and server, giving all the power to the user. On the middleware side it extends even more the ecosystem with multiple components.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD API Gateway on Kubernetes - Deployment Guide</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-on-kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2018 18:47:03 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-on-kubernetes/</guid><description>In this article we are going to show how to configure and deploy the KrakenD API Gateway in a kubernetes environment.
We will use for the demonstration Minikube so you cant test it in your own local machine.
Let&amp;rsquo;s get started!
Setting up a local Kubernetes We will run Kubernetes locally thanks to Minikube. Just follow the README in the project for the installation and the Quickstart section. Installing minikube it&amp;rsquo;s quick and easy.</description></item><item><title>Website development as a sysadmin</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/website-development-as-a-sysadmin/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2018 16:18:25 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/website-development-as-a-sysadmin/</guid><description>As a systems administrator for the past 15 years, I&amp;rsquo;m not very used to web development as this kind of work has been usually done by other colleagues in every company I&amp;rsquo;ve worked for. I wanted to create a web application myself using an external API, as an exercise to go out my comfort zone.
Some time ago I found that Marvel Comics has a REST API where you can get a lot of information about comics, characters, authors and other interesting information.</description></item><item><title>Edge computing - A story of buses, IoT, and API gateways</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-on-raspberry/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 21:25:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-on-raspberry/</guid><description>The IoT industry has been running for some years now adding millions of devices into the network. The range of devices and capabilities is very wide and heterogeneous, from small devices powered with a 9-volt battery to track the location of freight shippings traveling the oceans (using platforms like Sigfox) to permanently plugged devices with more powerful computing like a Raspberry Pi where computation cycles are not a problem.
Generally speaking, all these devices collect raw data and send it to the cloud where big data centers process it.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD Golang Plugins - Extending the Functionality</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-golang-plugins/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 22:07:03 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-golang-plugins/</guid><description>The release of golang 1.8 more than a year ago opened the door to loading dynamic linked components in run time, and we were keen to find out if we could include this great feature in our KrakenD toolbox.
We&amp;rsquo;d like to share our experience and details on how we enhanced our products to support golang plugins.
Why would anyone use plugins in Go? The plugin concept is widely known and supported in several programming languages and environments.</description></item><item><title>Deploying and versioning an API Gateway</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/deploying-an-api-gateway/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 23:46:25 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/deploying-an-api-gateway/</guid><description>When it comes to maintaining and deploying an API Gateway within an organization, you should always be aware of best practice. A gateway is an extra step between the client and the servers with the power to define a whole new interface, yet it&amp;rsquo;s so flexible and easy to implement that you might be tempted to start creating API interfaces without thinking about it - and end up creating problems for the future.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD 0.4 release notes</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-0.4-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2018 14:50:53 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-0.4-release-notes/</guid><description>KrakenD 0.4 materializes the announcement we did 3 months ago by going full open source and public releasing the former enterprise-only components.
This release note comprehends both the KrakenD framework and the KrakenD Community Edition binary distribution.
KrakenD framework The KrakenD framework, engine of the KrakenD API Gateway. The summary of changes introduced in the 0.4 are:
Removed ALL external dependencies and placed to krakend-contrib repositories Decoder and Service Discovery register system Response metadata Response decoder and formatter exposed Custom status code handler Minor handler optimizations Config version upgraded Server configuration extended (with timeouts and limits) Now non strict REST urls are allowed Request and response manipulation optimized func version for all the interfaces Link to 0.</description></item><item><title>An API Gateway is not the new Unicorn</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/what-is-an-api-gateway/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 10:10:53 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/what-is-an-api-gateway/</guid><description>The more we talk to people about API gateways, the more we have come to realize that the term means different things to different people, and more specifically we see a growing trend where developers (but mostly managers) expect an API gateway to be able to perform miracles, usually a long way away from its intended use.
It&amp;rsquo;s as if the API Gateway is the new unicorn that will solve all problems and make everything wonderful in the microservices scene.</description></item><item><title>Road to KrakenD 0.4</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/road-to-0.4/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2017 12:10:53 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/road-to-0.4/</guid><description>The next iteration of KrakenD is right around the corner and the Devops Faith team and the rest of the community we are working together to launch the 0.4 release before end of year. The jump from the 0.3.9 of the binary and the 0.3 of the framework to the 0.4 will bring a lot of interesting stuff but we also need to do a remarkable change in the code for a brighter future: kill external dependencies with fire.</description></item><item><title>Automating Linux Packaging for KrakenD API Gateway</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/automating-linux-packaging/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2017 12:43:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/automating-linux-packaging/</guid><description>Everyone loves reaching the maximum number of available platforms for their software but this usually comes at a cost. In this article we will explain how we generated our packaging for Linux in an automated fashion, being faithful to our DevOps dogma.
Dockerize all the things! Our dev team uses both Linux and MacOS X in desktop machines and KrakenD has been running and behaving in the same way in all the platforms because from day one we decided to run everything on Docker.</description></item><item><title>Open sourcing all 1st-year enterprise components</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/open-sourcing-enterprise-features/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2017 19:01:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/open-sourcing-enterprise-features/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been almost one year live, and what is known today as the KrakenD Enterprise components will be disclosed in the form of open-source repositories in the following weeks, and the action has already started, don&amp;rsquo;t miss it! In this post, we will explain the reasons behind this decision which might sound crazy from a business perspective in the first place. Why would anyone publish one year of paid software as free software?</description></item></channel></rss>