<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>KrakenD API Gateway Case Study on KrakenD - Open source API Gateway</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/case-study/</link><description>Recent content in KrakenD API Gateway Case Study on KrakenD - Open source API Gateway</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.krakend.io/case-study/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Suvoda Case Study: Scaling eClinical Integrations</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/case-study/suvoda/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/case-study/suvoda/</guid><description>Faced with the task of streamlining external integration workflows for its global clinical trial technology platform, Suvoda encountered a challenging landscape. The clinical trials the platform supports are often highly complex and operate on tight timelines.
Unifying a fast-growing API ecosystem Suvoda needed a more efficient way to manage third party integrations with other clinical technology provider solutions. The objective: create a single integration layer that simplifies client connectivity, scales effortlessly, and enforces consistent security and governance.</description></item><item><title>Neo4j Case Study: Scaling Internal API Infrastructure</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/case-study/neo4j/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/case-study/neo4j/</guid><description>KrakenD doesn’t try to do too much. That’s a feature, not a bug. Other gateways make complexity the default—you end up needing UIs just to manage their bloat. KrakenD is the opposite: well-documented, simple, powerful. It just works.
Challenge: Taming API Chaos Across Teams As Neo4j’s internal APIs rapidly multiplied across development teams, the complexity of managing secure, scalable access grew unsustainable. The existing API gateway setup lacked the flexibility needed to address authentication workflows consistently across services.</description></item><item><title>How Diebold Nixdorf Simplified their Retail API Platform</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/case-study/diebold-nixdorf/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/case-study/diebold-nixdorf/</guid><description>I appreciate solutions that strike the right balance between power and simplicity. KrakenD does exactly that, and more. It’s now an integral part of our digital infrastructure.
The Challenge: Simplifying API Exposure at Scale Within the Retail vertical, Diebold Nixdorf needed to expose a new generation of public-facing APIs. These APIs serve internal Customer Services teams and, in some cases, customers directly. The goals: fast performance, low operational overhead, and architectural flexibility.</description></item><item><title>MyCarrier: One Powerful API for Smarter Logistics</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/case-study/mycarrier/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/case-study/mycarrier/</guid><description>MyCarrier is a technology-driven logistics company dedicated to carrier management. By connecting shippers directly with carriers through its platform, MyCarrier empowers businesses to simplify their shipping operations and access real-time rates, shipping data, and carrier information.
Unifying Microservices into a Single, Manageable API Gateway To maintain a streamlined, secure, and high-performance interface, MyCarrier needed an API gateway that could unify multiple microservices into a single public-facing API, deployed in their existing Kubernetes ecosystem.</description></item><item><title>lastminute.com Case Study: Success Story</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/case-study/lastminute/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/case-study/lastminute/</guid><description>In lastminute.com, KrakenD played a vital role in our API transformation journey by protecting our business platforms boundary and exposing the business capabilities in a standard way to both internal and external audience &amp;ndash; Stefano Leopizzi
Background Over the past decade, lastminute.com has evolved its production architecture, shifting from a traditional approach to a more flexible and scalable system.
As part of this continuous evolution, lastminute.com identified opportunities to enhance governance and streamline interactions across its growing ecosystem of hundreds of microservices.</description></item><item><title>DigitalRoute Case Study: Success Story</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/case-study/digitalroute/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/case-study/digitalroute/</guid><description>DigitalRoute has long been a leader in transforming raw usage data into revenue, with its Cloud Edition SaaS platform earning a stellar reputation for reliability and performance. But as they expanded their product portfolio to offer public APIs, the company faced a critical challenge: how to support their new &amp;ldquo;Usage Metering&amp;rdquo; feature efficiently, allowing customers to interact with their system via APIs instead of the traditional user interface.
The Turning Point: From Internal to Public APIs Before KrakenD, DigitalRoute&amp;rsquo;s system leaned heavily on internal APIs, supported by a custom-built gateway that worked well for backend needs but wasn&amp;rsquo;t equipped to handle public-facing demands.</description></item><item><title>Coop Atlantique Case Study: Success Story</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/case-study/coop-atlantique/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/case-study/coop-atlantique/</guid><description>We began by creating a model with the community version to assess its capabilities. Once we confirmed that this tool met our needs, we opted for an enterprise license. Simply to benefit from tools that facilitate integration into our model and address specific requirements of our architecture in terms of security, data transformation, and authentication management. &amp;ndash; Nicolas Gabetty
Coop Atlantique is a supermarket and hypermarket specialist who faced several challenges in integrating SAP with their service architecture while ensuring secure, scalable exposure of APIs.</description></item><item><title>Bloom Credit: Multi-Provider API Security with KrakenD</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/case-study/bloom-credit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/case-study/bloom-credit/</guid><description>I want to highlight the exceptional support KrakenD provides. We can always expect prompt and thorough responses, I believe this has definitely accelerated our development speed and allowed us to find the right KrakenD feature that fits our needs. &amp;ndash; Akanksha Nichrelay, Senior Engineer
Bloom Credit simplifies credit-related services for financial institutions, fintechs and other businesses consuming or producing credit data. Their platform abstracts the complexities of credit bureau connectivity, enabling compliant credit inquiries and accurate payment reporting to the major US credit bureaus.</description></item><item><title>Jobteaser Case Study: Scalable Public APIs with KrakenD</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/case-study/jobteaser/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/case-study/jobteaser/</guid><description>The versatility of KrakenD allows us to use it as a &amp;lsquo;one size fits all&amp;rsquo; solution. We’ve been able to migrate all our legacy API endpoints seamlessly, and it’s now the main gateway for our services and partners alike.
The JobTeaser tech ecosystem was initiated more than a decade ago. If our platform was initially a Ruby on Rails monolith, now we manage a fleet of ever-growing services built using Ruby and Go.</description></item><item><title>OnchainPLM Case Study: Success Story</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/case-study/onchainplm/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/case-study/onchainplm/</guid><description>OnchainPLM is a product lifecycle management (PLM) solutions provider that specializes in serving the semiconductor industry among other sectors and a leader in cloud-native technology development, that has modernized its business gateway integration with KrakenD. This case study delves into their use of our API gateway to address unique business challenges, highlighting the effectiveness of KrakenD in improving service delivery and operational efficiency.
Facing the challenge Initially, OnchainPLM faced the challenge of customizing their existing business gateways to better suit their needs.</description></item><item><title>Instill AI Case Study: Success Story</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/case-study/instill/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/case-study/instill/</guid><description>Initial Challenges In our pursuit of harnessing unstructured data&amp;rsquo;s value, we faced challenges in our microservice architecture that required a portable, lightweight, and high-performance API Gateway solution. This was crucial for maintaining real-time end-to-end requirements while ensuring seamless integration with our existing technologies. Our Scenario
KrakenD emerged as the perfect solution for our needs. We seamlessly integrated KrakenD into both Instill Core and Instill Cloud&amp;rsquo;s API Gateways. This integration not only improved our microservice architecture&amp;rsquo;s efficiency but also streamlined our entire data processing pipeline.</description></item><item><title>Bikefolder Case Study: Success Story</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/case-study/bikefolder/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/case-study/bikefolder/</guid><description>With nearly a century of experience in bike retail, distribution, brand management, sport performance, and product design, BikeFolder.com has taken the pedal off the metal and shifted gears towards digital transformation. Transcending the typical CRM framework, BikeFolder.com is a universal platform fostering neutrality and connecting bike owners, retailers, and manufacturers in a cohesive environment. It optimizes interactions, streamlines inventories, service histories, and appointments while providing invaluable data for manufacturers to catalyze innovation.</description></item><item><title>Rainbow Smile Case Study: Success Story</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/case-study/rainbow-smile/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/case-study/rainbow-smile/</guid><description>To us, KrakenD is an enterprise system that forgives mistakes and allows you to get the desired result.
The challenges At &amp;ldquo;Rainbow Smile&amp;rdquo;, we faced challenges with publishing technical APIs from external sources, leading to increased development costs and a violation of the Domain Driven Design. We also needed help publishing the REST interface, which required developer involvement.
Scenario To solve these challenges, we implemented KrakenD as a gateway for systems that do not support gRPC.</description></item><item><title>Child Rescue Coalition Case Study: Success Story</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/case-study/child-rescue-coalition/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/case-study/child-rescue-coalition/</guid><description>The technology CRC develops is designed to monitor areas of the internet not owned by a corporate entity but primarily driven by computers that are connected to a network. Since there is no corporate ownership of this technology, there is no consistent or easy way to report abuse. CRC has trained more than 12,000 investigators across 98 countries on their technology which has led to the arrest of 14,000 individuals and the rescue of more than 3,200 children.</description></item><item><title>Rappi - KrakenD API Gateway Case Study</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/case-study/rappi/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/case-study/rappi/</guid><description>Rappi is an application that helps users with their everyday shopping needs. From restaurants, supermarkets, pharmacies, spirits, travel, delivery, fintech products, and more.
Scenario At the technical level, Rappi is a large e-commerce platform and one of the top 100 AWS resource consumers worldwide, running over 7000 EC2 servers and over 1800 nodes on EKS.
Their stack runs on Amazon on a dual combination of ECS and Kubernetes. +750 developers of all sorts are allowed to choose their coding language, and the Infra team (Cloud Engineering - 70 people) provides the necessary tools to make it a reality.</description></item><item><title>Pretty Technical Case Study: Success Story</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/case-study/pretty-technical/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/case-study/pretty-technical/</guid><description>Pretty Technical has specialists providing consultancy and services for the finance and gaming industries.
Pretty Technical has a focus on simplicity and automation, and at the same time, they develop their business tools using microservices, separating concerns. Yet, all the applications need to combine all these services, which is where KrakenD fits like a glove.
Results, Return on Investment and Future Plans After researching the best tool for the job, Pretty Technical adopted KrakenD in the early stages of development in 2021.</description></item><item><title>AlfaStrakhovanie Case Study - Success Stories</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/case-study/alfa-strakhovanie/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/case-study/alfa-strakhovanie/</guid><description>AlfaStrakhovanie has adopted KrakenD as its gateway solution as it checks all its requirements regarding features, connectivity, source code control, security, and deployment choice using a DevOps approach.
The following video is an event recording that compares KrakenD with other solutions. It explains the reasons behind having chosen KrakenD and how it improved the existing gateway solution before that.
It covers the company dimension, numbers, methodology, and several requirements for deployment in Kubernetes, as well as which are the most liked features, and a walk-through covering the KrakenD Designer.</description></item><item><title>Afosto Case Study: Success Story</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/case-study/afosto/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/case-study/afosto/</guid><description>Afosto is one of the main software (SaaS) solutions empowering omnichannel commerce for retailers in The Netherlands. Our software empowers over 150 store owners with selling online and offline. Two years ago we started the transition towards an API-first development paradigm, currently powered by over 90 cloud-native microservices. KrakenD has enabled us to make this shift naturally.
Challenges KrakenD helps solve Commerce is always challenging. We have to deal with sudden spikes in traffic, payments, ever-changing regulations, and large amounts of data for analytics.</description></item><item><title>4data Case Study: Success Story</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/case-study/4data/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/case-study/4data/</guid><description>4data provides tailored cloud services to solve specific problems without mandating customers to increase their local infrastructure footprint. All these services can be managed remotely via our management application running in the browser only and communicating via REST APIs. This is where KrakenD joins the game to protect our backend REST API endpoints, both internal and external.
The main challenge was to protect endpoints from unauthenticated access. Wherever required, KrakenD applies JWT validation to ensure only authenticated requests are reaching the backend services.</description></item><item><title>Xiachufang (下厨房) Case Study: Success Story</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/case-study/xiachufang/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/case-study/xiachufang/</guid><description>With around 70 million unique users, Xiachufang is the biggest cuisine community in China, making it possible for its users to share home recipes easily, watch video courses made by experts, and shop ingredients or kitchenware.
Xiachufang&amp;rsquo;s requirements at the beginning of its API gateway research were:
Being able to efficiently distribute the requests A simple and stateless approach to API gateway Strong customization capabilities An efficient and programmatic way to define rules Supporting monitoring and alarms Support the traffic and scalability needs of the company Xiachufang started with a small subset of live services (small as in nearly 2,000 requests per second) before starting moving more services to KrakenD:</description></item><item><title>Hepsiburada Case Study - Success Stories</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/case-study/hepsiburada/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/case-study/hepsiburada/</guid><description>Hepsiburada is the largest and fastest-growing e-commerce platform in Turkey and the top 5 in Europe. With over 150 million monthly visits and over 50 million product variations in mobile phones, cosmetics, consumer goods, fashion, and more, Hepsiburada is a business and technology leader in Turkey.
Hepsiburada challenges A company of such dimensions as Hepsiburada had several challenges before choosing KrakenD as their API gateway solution:
Operating 500 microservices and 40+ autonomous product development teams has many complex issues.</description></item><item><title>Perx Case Study: Success Story</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/case-study/perx/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/case-study/perx/</guid><description>Perx is developing a data management platform called Hoop built on microservices and an architecture that makes use of extensive internal and external communications through REST APIs and asynchronous NATS channels.
KrakenD API Gateway offers robust functionality to control the traffic between external API clients and services. It aggregates microservices responses together into one unified API and thus provides flexible options for request/response manipulation to meet customers&amp;rsquo; needs.
Using KrakenD provides secure external connections with OAuth.</description></item><item><title>Privalia Case Study: Success Story</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/case-study/privalia/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/case-study/privalia/</guid><description>Veepee is the European flash sales leader with 72M of members, and Privalia its strategic brand for Spain, Italy, Brazil, and Mexico.
Privalia, with +13M members, evolved their customer care solution from an in-house solution to a Salesforce integration with their internal systems.
Before KrakenD, the main challenge of Veepee was to integrate Salesforce with multiple microservices and handle authorization, security, and aggregation in the middle layers.
KrakenD solved this challenge with out of the box features, keeping Privalia&amp;rsquo;s logic separated, and decoupled from Salesforce.</description></item><item><title>i2S by GFI Case Study: Success Story</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/case-study/i2s/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/case-study/i2s/</guid><description>GFI is one of the most high-performing IT and digital service companies in the market. Their insurance branch i2S has software solutions installed in nearly 50 insurance companies (Life and Non-life) and several pension fund management societies.
KrakenD is the entry point to consume all the micro-services in a controlled way and helps create an insurance-related product, covering many aspects, from legal to finance and actuarial.
KrakenD unifies and aggregates the responses of all the underlying Java microservices, and injects custom middleware for insurance&amp;rsquo;s particular use case.</description></item><item><title>Open Room Inc Case Study: Success Story</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/case-study/openroom/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/case-study/openroom/</guid><description>Open Room Inc. uses KrakenD to expose easily and safely various Real Estate applications, to help agents in their daily work and end-users to find the home they are looking for.
Open Room uses image processing, character recognition, document analysis, and machine learning.
KrakenD API Gateway helped Open Room to reduce the latency of all queries by grouping backend queries by frontend use-case, and allowed Open Room to build their API simply and coherently.</description></item><item><title>Adevinta Spain Case Study: Success Story</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/case-study/adevinta/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/case-study/adevinta/</guid><description>Adevinta Spain handles a vast amount of traffic, as it operates marketplaces with 18 million active users. The adoption of KrakenD&amp;rsquo;s technology in production started in early 2017 and has been running since then.
Adevinta was investigating how to get more performance in their company-wide solution, and how to provide autonomy to non backend teams.
After several weeks of research, stress-tests and benchmarking several products in the market, Adevinta decided to choose KrakenD as the api gateway engine.</description></item><item><title>Delivery Club (Mail.ru group) Case Study: Success Story</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/case-study/mailru/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/case-study/mailru/</guid><description>Delivery Club, a Mail.ru brand, is the largest online food delivery platform in Russia, moving food from thousands of restaurants to homes in more than 100 cities.
Delivery Club processes +30,000 orders per day, 72% of which are made from mobile devices.
The technology is built using a modernized microservices architecture with around 20 services, including KrakenD API Gateway that sits between end users and Delivery Club&amp;rsquo;s services.
KrakenD&amp;rsquo;s main duty is processing ingoing and outgoing traffic making sure that user sessions are properly authorized when needed, and discarding malicious activity and hacking attempts.</description></item><item><title>Dusdusan.com (Indonesia) Case Study: Success Story</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/case-study/dusdusan/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/case-study/dusdusan/</guid><description>Established in the Jakarta City of Indonesia in November 2015, PT. Dusdusan Dotcom Indonesia is a mobile Internet company engaged in the research, development, and operation of E-business platform.
As a leader of membership E-business in Indonesia, Dusdusan.com, together with many domestic and foreign top brands and quality emerging brands, has integrated into the life of thousands of Indonesian families.
As the business developed rapidly, Dusdusan.com needs to keep improving its platform.</description></item><item><title>Letgo Case Study: Success Story</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/case-study/letgo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/case-study/letgo/</guid><description>Letgo is the biggest and fastest-growing app for buying and selling locally.
Letgo is a desktop application (SPA) and a mobile application with native implementations for every operating system. As Letgo&amp;rsquo;s organization is large, the UI experience of each client (Android, iOS, web&amp;hellip;) is handled by a different team.
Letgo uses different clusters and configurations of KrakenD API Gateway per client, allowing each team to have its customized views of merged data.</description></item><item><title>Pearson Education Case Study: Success Story</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/case-study/pearson/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/case-study/pearson/</guid><description>Pearson Central Europe has trusted KrakenD as its API Gateway solution for the Parent App, which provides parents with a wide range of resources, including podcasts, infographics, quizzes, and checklists, to support their children&amp;rsquo;s progress in learning.
KrakenD API Gateway offers the endpoints to the Parent App and sits between end-users and the Pearson services, which provide all the data that KrakenD aggregates to supply the use case.
KrakenD handles OAuth with HMAC security and implements minor custom middlewares to fit the desired end-user consumption of the services.</description></item><item><title>MTS Travel Case Study: Success Story</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/case-study/mts-travel/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/case-study/mts-travel/</guid><description>At MTS Travel, we needed an API gateway solution to support our microservices architecture and provide a single access point for API clients. After evaluating the available options, we chose KrakenD for its speed, extensibility, and open-source principle. In this case study, we&amp;rsquo;ll discuss why we decided on KrakenD, our experience using the solution, and the complexities we encountered. &amp;ndash; Vladimir Kalugin, Backend Lead Developer
Why did we choose KrakenD?</description></item><item><title>iContainers Case Study: Success Story</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/case-study/icontainers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 17:23:05 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/case-study/icontainers/</guid><description>iContainers is an ocean freight forwarder that allows you to compare, book, manage, and track maritime shipments in real-time without intermediaries.
As importers and exporters combine more than 500,000 rates and maritime transport routes from different providers, KrakenD plays the role of a Backend for Frontend in several SPAs. Some examples are the back-office, the partners portal, or the pricing API.
KrakenD&amp;rsquo;s primary duty in all these cases is to provide a reliable way to fetch data from multiple providers and APIs and merge the results of all the services into useful endpoints.</description></item></channel></rss>