<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>company on KrakenD - Open source API Gateway</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/tags/company/</link><description>Recent content in company on KrakenD - Open source API Gateway</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.krakend.io/tags/company/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>KrakenD framework becomes a Linux Foundation project</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-framework-joins-the-linux-foundation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-framework-joins-the-linux-foundation/</guid><description>Today, together with the Linux Foundation, we are announcing that the KrakenD framework, our core engine, has been donated to the Linux Foundation and is now the &amp;ldquo;Lura Project.&amp;quot;
The Lura Project&amp;rsquo;s mission is to offer an extendable, simple, and stateless high-performance API Gateway framework designed for cloud-native and on-prem setups. Rather than solving a specific use case, Lura provides a library of components, a framework for assembling them into custom API gateway systems like a Lego set.</description></item><item><title>Albert Garcia to expand KrakenD business.</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/albert-garcia-expand-krakend-business/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/albert-garcia-expand-krakend-business/</guid><description>Today, we are announcing that Albert Garcia recently joined KrakenD as Director of Business Development and member of the Board.
In his role, he will identify and develop new business opportunities to help expand even more the presence of KrakenD. Garcia will spearhead new markets and emerging trends, sales, and client relationship management, to name a few.
Having worked previously with him for more than 15 years, we know that Garcia is the right person at the right time for KrakenD.</description></item></channel></rss>