<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>company on KrakenD - Open source API Gateway</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/tags/company/</link><description>Recent content in company on KrakenD - Open source API Gateway</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.krakend.io/tags/company/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>KrakenD becomes a CNA (CVE Numbering Authority)</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-becomes-a-cna/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-becomes-a-cna/</guid><description>The Spanish National Cybersecurity Institute (INCIBE) announces today the addition of KrakenD as a CNA (CVE Numbering Authority). KrakenD assumes as its own, from this date, the best practices of this program.
KrakenD is now authorized by the CVE Program to assign CVE identifiers within its scope and its corresponding publication in the CNA section. Information technology and cybersecurity professionals use CVE Records to ensure they are discussing the same issue, and to coordinate their efforts to prioritize and address the vulnerabilities.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD partners with Child Rescue Coalition</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-child-rescue-coalition-partnership/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-child-rescue-coalition-partnership/</guid><description>Barcelona, September 19th 2022.- KrakenD announces today the partnership with Child Rescue Coalition. Child Rescue Coalition (CRC) is a nonprofit organization whose mission is to rescue children from sexual abuse by building technology for law enforcement to track, arrest and prosecute child predators. KrakenD has donated an unlimited commercial license (KrakenD Enterprise) to CRC to help them build and scale their APIs-oriented technological platform.
CRC has contributed to rescuing more than 3,200 children from sexual exploitation and abuse.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD Now Available on Auth0 Marketplace</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-auth0-announcement/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-auth0-announcement/</guid><description>Barcelona – 15th June 2020 – KrakenD today announced the availability of its API Gateway on Auth0 Marketplace, a catalog of trusted technology integrations to extend the functionality of Auth0’s identity management platform. KrakenD offers an ultra-performant API Gateway that allows companies to effortlessly adopt a microservices architecture through a powerful engine that can transform, aggregate, and remove data from their own or third-party services.
The KrakenD API Gateway serves as a unified interface for managing incoming API requests and connecting to the correct destination, while supporting functionalities across security, authorization, traffic management, observability, and load balancing, among others.</description></item><item><title>KrakenD framework becomes a Linux Foundation project</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-framework-joins-the-linux-foundation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/krakend-framework-joins-the-linux-foundation/</guid><description>Today, together with the Linux Foundation, we are announcing that the KrakenD framework, our core engine, has been donated to the Linux Foundation and is now the &amp;ldquo;Lura Project.&amp;rdquo;
The Lura Project&amp;rsquo;s mission is to offer an extendable, simple, and stateless high-performance API Gateway framework designed for cloud-native and on-prem setups. Rather than solving a specific use case, Lura provides a library of components, a framework for assembling them into custom API gateway systems like a Lego set.</description></item><item><title>Albert Garcia to expand KrakenD business.</title><link>https://www.krakend.io/blog/albert-garcia-expand-krakend-business/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.krakend.io/blog/albert-garcia-expand-krakend-business/</guid><description>Today, we are announcing that Albert Garcia recently joined KrakenD as Director of Business Development and member of the Board.
In his role, he will identify and develop new business opportunities to help expand even more the presence of KrakenD. Garcia will spearhead new markets and emerging trends, sales, and client relationship management, to name a few.
Having worked previously with him for more than 15 years, we know that Garcia is the right person at the right time for KrakenD.</description></item></channel></rss>